def load_okurigana
  Yamafuda.find_or_create_by(name: 'okurigana kanji').fuda = [
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "一つ", back: "ひとつ
  one;  
    (Noun) for one thing (often used in itemized lists);
  (after a noun) only;
  (with a verb in negative form) (not) even;  
    (Adverbial noun) just (i.e. \"just try it\")"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "二つ", back: "ふたつ
  two"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "九つ", back: "ここのつ
  nine"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "入る", back: "い.る, -い.る, はい.る
  enter, insert"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "入り", back: "いり
  entering;
  setting (of the sun);
  containing; content; audience;
  income;
  beginning"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "入れる", back: "いれる
  to put in; to let in; to take in; to bring in; to insert; to set (a jewel, etc.); to ink in (e.g. a tattoo);
  to admit; to accept; to employ; to hire;
  to accept; to comply; to grant; to adopt (a policy, etc.); to take (advice, etc.); to listen to; to pay attention to;
  to include;
  to pay (one's rent, etc.);
  to cast (a vote);
  to make (tea, coffee, etc.);
  to turn on (a switch, etc.);
  to send (a fax); to call"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "入れ", back: "いれ
  container; receptacle"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "八つ", back: "や.つ, やっ.つ
  eight, eight radical (no. 12)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "七つ", back: "ななつ
  seven"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "大きい", back: "おおきい
  big; large; great; loud"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "大いに", back: "おおいに
  very; much; greatly; a lot of"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "三つ", back: "みっつ
  three"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "上げる", back: "あげる
  to raise; to elevate;
  to do up (one's hair);
  to fly (a kite, etc.); to launch (fireworks, etc.); to surface (a submarine, etc.);
  to land (a boat);
  to show someone (into a room);
  to send someone (away);
  to enrol (one's child in school); to enroll;
  to increase (price, quality, status, etc.);
  to make (a loud sound); to raise (one's voice);
  to earn (something desirable);
  to praise;
  to give (an example, etc.); to cite;
  to summon up (all of one's energy, etc.);
  
    (Polite language)  to give;
  to offer up (incense, a prayer, etc.) to the gods (or Buddha, etc.);
  to bear (a child);
  to conduct (a ceremony, esp. a wedding);  () (of the tide) to come in;  
    () to vomit;  
    () 
    (Usually written using kana alone)   (Polite language)  to do for (the sake of someone else);  () to complete ...;
    (Humble (kenjougo) language)  to humbly do ..."),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "上がる", back: "あがる
  to rise; to go up; to come up; to ascend; to be raised;
  to enter (esp. from outdoors); to come in; to go in;
  to enter (a school); to advance to the next grade;
  to get out (of water); to come ashore;
  to increase;
  to improve; to make progress;
  to be promoted; to advance;
  to be made (of profit, etc.);
  to occur (esp. of a favourable result);
  to be adequate (to cover expenses, etc.);
  to be finished; to be done; to be over;
  (of rain) to stop; to lift;
  to stop (working properly); to cut out; to give out; to die;
  to win (in a card game, etc.);
  to be spoken loudly;
  to get stage fright;
  to be offered (to the gods, etc.);
  
    (Humble (kenjougo) language)  to go; to visit;
    (Honorific or respectful language)  to eat; to drink;
  to be listed (as a candidate);
  to serve (in one's master's home);
  (in Kyoto) to go north;  () (after the -masu stem of a verb) indicates completion"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "上がり", back: "あがり
  ascent; rise; slope;
  freshly-drawn green tea (esp. in sushi shops);
  advance income; crop yield;
  death; spinning; completion; stop; finish;
  after (rain); ex (official, etc.);
  (end) results (e.g. of crafts like painting, pottery, etc.); how something comes out"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "上る", back: "のぼ.る
  above, up"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "上り", back: "のぼり
  ascent; climbing; ascending (path); climb;
  up-train (e.g. going to Tokyo);  
    () northward (towards Tokyo)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "上せる", back: "のぼせる
  to raise; to record; to bring up (a matter); to serve  (Food term) ; to send some on out"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "上す", back: "のぼす
  to raise; to record; to bring up (a matter); to serve  (Food term) ; to send some one out"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "下げる", back: "さげる
  to hang; to lower; to move back; to wear; to dismiss; to grant"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "下がる", back: "さがる
  to hang down; to abate; to retire; to fall; to step back"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "下る", back: "くだ.る
  below, down, descend, give, low, inferior"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "下り", back: "くだり
  down-train (going away from Tokyo);
  down-slope; downward going"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "下す", back: "くだ.す, -くだ.す
  below, down, descend, give, low, inferior"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "下さる", back: "くださる
  to give; to confer"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "下ろす", back: "おろす
  to take down (e.g. flag); to launch (e.g. boat); to drop; to lower (e.g. ladder); to let (a person) off; to unload; to discharge;
  to drop off (a passenger from a vehicle); to let (a person) off;
  to withdraw money from an account;
  to wear (clothing) for the first time;
  to fillet (e.g. a fish)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "下りる", back: "おりる
  to descend (e.g. a mountain); to go down; to come down;
  to alight (e.g. from bus); to get off; to disembark; to dismount;
  to step down; to retire; to give up; to quit;
  to be granted; to be issued; to be given;
  to form (of frost, dew, mist, etc.);
  to be passed (from the body; i.e. of a roundworm)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "小さい", back: "ちいさい
  small; little; tiny"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "中る", back: "あたる
  to be hit; to strike;
  to touch; to be in contact; to be affixed;
  to be equivalent to; to be applicable; to apply to;
  to be right on the money (of a prediction, criticism, etc.);
  to be selected (in a lottery, etc.); to win;
  to be successful; to go well; to be a hit;
  to face; to confront;
  to lie (in the direction of);
  to undertake; to be assigned;
  to be stricken (by food poisoning, heat, etc.); to be afflicted;
  to be called upon (by the teacher);
  to treat (esp. harshly); to lash out at;
  to be unnecessary;
  (in baseball) to be hitting well; to be on a hitting streak;
  (in fishing) to feel a bite;
  (of fruit, etc.) to be bruised; to spoil;  
    () to feel (something) out; to probe into; to check (i.e. by comparison);
  to shave"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "五つ", back: "いつつ
  five"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "円い", back: "まる.い
  circle, yen, round"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "円か", back: "まどか
  round; tranquil"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "円やか", back: "まろやか
  round; circular; spherical;
  mild (taste); mellow (voice)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "六つ", back: "む.つ, むっ.つ
  six"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "出る", back: "でる
  to go out; to exit; to leave;
  to appear; to come forth; to be published;
  to answer (the phone or door)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "出す", back: "だす
  to take out; to get out;
  to put out; to reveal; to show;
  to submit (e.g. thesis); to turn in;
  to publish; to make public;
  to send (e.g. letter);
  to produce (a sound); to start (fire);
  to serve 
    (Food term) ;  (Suffix) to begin"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "出でる", back: "いでる
  to go; to come"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "出だす", back: "い.だす
  exit, leave, go out, come out, put out, protrude"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "生きる", back: "いきる
  to live; to exist;
  to make a living; to subsist;
  to be in effect; to be in use; to function;
  to come to life; to be enlivened;
  to be safe (in baseball, go, etc.)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "生かす", back: "いかす
  to make (the best) use of; to leverage (skills, attributes, experience, etc.); to capitalise on (experience, etc);
  to let live; to keep alive;
  to revive; to resuscitate"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "生ける", back: "いける
  to arrange (flowers); to plant;  
    (Noun or verb acting prenominally) living; live"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "生まれる", back: "うまれる
  to be born"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "生れる", back: "うまれる
  to be born"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "生まれ", back: "うまれ
  birth; birthplace"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "生む", back: "うむ
  to give birth; to deliver; to produce"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "生う", back: "おう
    (Archaism)  to grow; to spring up;
  to cut (teeth)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "生える", back: "はえる
  to grow; to spring up;
  to cut (teeth)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "生やす", back: "はやす
  to grow; to cultivate; to wear a beard"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "生る", back: "なる
  to bear fruit"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "生す", back: "な.す, む.す
  life, genuine, birth"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "四つ", back: "よっつ
  four"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "立つ", back: "たつ
  to stand; to rise; to stand up;
  to find oneself (e.g. in a difficult position);
  to depart (on a plane, train, etc.)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "立ち-", back: "た.ち-
  stand up, rise, set up, erect"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "立てる", back: "たてる
  to stand up; to put up; to set up; to erect; to raise;
  to thrust into; to bury into; to dig into;
  to make (a noise); to start (a rumour); to raise (a cloud of dust, etc.); to cause;
  to make; to establish; to set up; to develop; to formulate;
  to put up (a political candidate); to make (one's leader);
  to treat with respect;
  to sharpen; to make clear;
  to shut; to close;
  to make tea (macha); to perform the tea ceremony;
  to divide by;  
    () to do ... vigorously"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "立て-", back: "た.て-
  stand up, rise, set up, erect"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "立て", back: "-た.て, -だ.て
  stand up, rise, set up, erect"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "正しい", back: "ただしい
  right; just; correct; righteous; honest; truthful; proper; straightforward; perfect"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "正す", back: "ただす
  to correct; to reform; to amend; to redress;
  to adjust; to straighten;
  to ascertain; to confirm; to verify; to make sure of;
  to enquire of someone about something (inquire); to question"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "正に", back: "まさに
    (Usually written using kana alone)  exactly; surely; certainly;
  just (about to); on the verge (of doing or happening);
  duly; naturally"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "白い", back: "しろい
  white"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "先ず", back: "まず
    (Usually written using kana alone)  first (of all); to start with; about; almost; anyway; well; now;
  hardly (with neg. verb)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "早い", back: "はやい
  fast; quick; hasty; brisk;
  early (in the day, etc.); premature;
  (too) soon; not yet; (too) early;
  easy; simple; quick"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "早まる", back: "はやまる
  to move ahead (three hours, etc.); to move up;
  to quicken; to speed up; to gather speed;
  to be hasty; to be rash"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "早める", back: "はやめる
  to hasten; to quicken; to expedite; to precipitate; to accelerate"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "休む", back: "やすむ
  to be absent; to take a day off;
  to rest; to have a break;
  to go to bed; to (lie down to) sleep; to turn in; to retire;
  to stop doing some ongoing activity for a time; to suspend business"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "休まる", back: "やすまる
  to be rested; to feel at ease; to repose; to be relieved"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "休める", back: "やすめる
  to rest; to suspend; to give relief"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "見る", back: "みる
  to see; to look; to watch; to view; to observe;
  to look over; to look on; to assess; to examine; to judge;
    (Usually written using kana alone)  to look after; to keep an eye on; to take care of;
  to view (e.g. flowers, movie);
    (Usually written using kana alone)  to try;
    (Usually written using kana alone)  to see that...; to find that..."),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "見える", back: "み.える
  see, hopes, chances, idea, opinion, look at, visible"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "見せる", back: "みせる
  to show; to display"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "足りる", back: "たりる
  to be sufficient; to be enough;
  to be worth doing; to be worthy;
  to be sufficient; to answer; to do"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "足る", back: "たる
  to be sufficient; to be enough; to be worthy of"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "足す", back: "たす
  to add (numbers);
  to add (something); to top up (with something);
  to take care of (e.g. one's business)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "赤い", back: "あかい
  red;
  Red (i.e. communist)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "赤らむ", back: "あからむ
  to become red; to redden; to blush"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "赤らめる", back: "あからめる
  to blush; to redden"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "学ぶ", back: "まなぶ
  to study (in depth); to learn; to take lessons in"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "空く", back: "あ.く, す.く
  empty, sky, void, vacant, vacuum"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "空き", back: "あき
  space; room; emptiness; gap;
  opening; vacancy; empty seat;
  free time; time to spare;
  disuse; unused thing"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "空ける", back: "あ.ける
  empty, sky, void, vacant, vacuum"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "空かす", back: "すかす
  to feel hungry; to get hungry"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "空しい", back: "むなしい
  vacant; futile; vain; void; empty; ineffective; lifeless"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "青い", back: "あおい
  blue; green;
  pale;
  unripe; inexperienced"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "丸める", back: "まるめる
  to make round; to roll up; to curl up;
  to seduce; to cajole; to explain away;
  to round off (a fraction);
    (Archaism)  to lump together"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "丸い", back: "まる.い
  round, full (month), perfection, -ship, pills, make round, roll up, curl up, seduce, explain away"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "分ける", back: "わける
  to divide (into); to split (into); to part; to separate; to divide up; to classify; to sort out; to divide out;
  to share; to distribute; to deal out; to dish out;
  to distinguish; to discriminate; to differentiate (between);
  to break up (a fight); to mediate;
  to call a draw; to tie;
  to push one's way through (a crowd);
  to sell"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "分け", back: "わけ
  sharing; division;
  draw; tie"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "分かれる", back: "わかれる
  to branch; to fork; to diverge;
  to separate; to split; to divide;
  to disperse; to scatter"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "分かる", back: "わかる
  to be understood; to be comprehended; to be grasped;
  to become clear; to be known; to be discovered; to be realized; to be realised; to be found out"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "分かつ", back: "わかつ
  to divide; to separate;
  to share; to distribute;
  to distinguish"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "引く", back: "ひく
  to pull;
  to draw (attention, etc.); to attract (interest, etc.);
  to draw back;
  to draw (a card);
  to draw (plan, line, etc.);
  to catch (cold);
  to play (string instr.);
  to look up (e.g. dictionary); to consult;  
    () to haul; to pull (vehicles);
  to subtract;
  to ebb; to fade;
  to descend (from); to inherit (a characteristic);
  to quote; to raise (as evidence);
  to lay (a cable); to draw (a cable)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "引き", back: "ひ.き, -び.き
  pull, tug, jerk, admit, install, quote, refer to"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "引き-", back: "ひ.き-
  pull, tug, jerk, admit, install, quote, refer to"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "引ける", back: "ひける
  to close; to be over; to break up (e.g. school)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "少ない", back: "すくない
  few; a little; scarce; insufficient; seldom"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "少し", back: "すこし
  small quantity; little; few; something;
  little while;
  short distance"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "止まる", back: "と.まる, とど.まる
  stop, halt"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "止まり", back: "-ど.まり
  stop, halt"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "止める", back: "と.める, -と.める, とど.める, や.める
  stop, halt"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "止め", back: "-ど.め, とど.め
  stop, halt"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "止む", back: "やむ
  to cease; to stop; to be over"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "止す", back: "よ.す, -さ.す
  stop, halt"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "止し", back: "-さ.し
  stop, halt"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "切る", back: "きる
  to cut (usu. to cut through);
  to sever (connections, ties);
  to turn off (i.e. the light);
  to terminate (i.e. a conversation); to hang up (the phone); to disconnect;
  to punch (a ticket); to tear off (a stub);
  to open (something sealed);
  to start;
  to set (a limit);
  to reduce; to decrease; to discount;
  to shake off (water, etc.); to let drip-dry (or drain);
  to cross;
  to do (something noticeable);
  to turn (a vehicle);
  to cut (the ball);
  to shuffle (cards);
  to trump;
  (in Go) to isolate (an opponent's stone);  
    () (after the -masu stem of a verb) to finish; to complete"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "切り", back: "きり
  end; finish; stop;
  bounds; limits;
  delivery date (of a futures contract);
  finale (of a noh song); end of an act (in joruri or kabuki); final performance of the day (in vaudeville);  
    () counter for slices (esp. thick slices); counter for cuts (e.g. fish, meat);  
    (Particle)  (Usually written using kana alone)  only; just;
    (Usually written using kana alone)  since;
    (Usually written using kana alone)  remaining (in a particular state)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "切れる", back: "きれる
  to break; to snap; to be cut; to split; to crack;
  to be injured;
  to wear out; to be worn out;
  to break; to burst; to collapse;
  to wear off; to stop working; to go dead;
  to expire (time limit, etc.); to run out; to become due;
  to run out (of stock, etc.); to be exhausted; to be used up; to be sold out; to be out of;
  to be broken off (e.g. of a relationship); to break up; to have severed ties; to be cut off; to be disconnected;
  to cut well; to be sharp;
  to be sharp-minded; to be keen; to be shrewd; to be quick-witted; to be able;
  to be short of; to drop under (a certain figure); to beat (e.g. a record time);
  to dry off;
  to curve; to veer;
  to shuffle (cards);
  
    (Colloquialism)  to get angry; to snap; to blow one's top; to lose one's temper; to flip;  () to be able to do completely"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "切れ", back: "き.れ, -き.れ, -ぎ.れ
  cut, cutoff, be sharp"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "太い", back: "ふとい
  fat; thick;
  deep (of a voice);
  daring; shameless; brazen;
    (Slang)  lucky (billiards)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "太る", back: "ふとる
  to grow fat (stout, plump); to become fat; to gain weight"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "外す", back: "はずす
  to unfasten; to undo;
  to remove; to take off; to deinstall;
  to leave; to step out; to slip away;
  to miss (a target)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "外れる", back: "はずれる
  to be disconnected; to get out of place; to be off; to be out (e.g. of gear)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "用いる", back: "もちいる
  to use; to make use of; to utilize; to utilise"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "半ば", back: "なかば
  middle; half; semi; halfway; partly"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "広い", back: "ひろい
  spacious; vast; wide"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "広まる", back: "ひろまる
  to spread; to be propagated"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "広める", back: "ひろめる
  to broaden; to propagate"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "広がる", back: "ひろがる
  to spread (out); to extend; to stretch; to reach to; to get around; to fill (e.g. a space)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "広げる", back: "ひろげる
  to spread; to extend; to expand; to enlarge; to widen; to broaden; to unfold; to open; to unroll"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "古い", back: "ふるい
  old (not person); aged; ancient; antiquated; stale; threadbare; outmoded; obsolete article"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "古す", back: "ふるす
  to wear out"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "会う", back: "あう
  to meet; to encounter;
    (Usually written using kana alone)  to have an accident; to have a bad experience"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "会わせる", back: "あわせる
  to make (someone) to meet; to let (someone) meet;
  to expose to; to subject to"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "会まる", back: "あつ.まる
  meeting, meet, party, association, interview, join"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "同じ", back: "おな.じ
  same, agree, equal"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "自ら", back: "みずか.ら
  oneself"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "自ずから", back: "おのずから
  naturally; as a matter of course"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "自ずと", back: "おのずと
  naturally"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "行く", back: "い.く, ゆ.く
  going, journey, carry out, conduct, act, line, row, bank"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "行き", back: "-ゆ.き, -い.き
  going, journey, carry out, conduct, act, line, row, bank"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "行う", back: "おこなう
  to perform; to do; to conduct oneself; to carry out"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "行なう", back: "おこなう
  to perform; to do; to conduct oneself; to carry out"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "合う", back: "あ.う, -あ.う
  fit, suit, join, 0.1"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "合い", back: "あい
  joint; associate; accomplice"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "合わす", back: "あわす
  to match (rhythm, speed, etc.);
  to join together; to unite; to combine; to add up;
  to face; to be opposite (someone);
  to compare; to check with;
  to cause to meet (e.g. an unpleasant fate);
  to place together; to connect; to overlap;
  to mix; to combine;
  to put blade to blade; to fight"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "合わせる", back: "あわせる
  to match (rhythm, speed, etc.);
  to join together; to unite; to combine; to add up;
  to face; to be opposite (someone);
  to compare; to check with;
  to cause to meet (e.g. an unpleasant fate);
  to place together; to connect; to overlap;
  to mix; to combine;
  to put blade to blade; to fight"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "回る", back: "まわ.る, -まわ.る, もとお.る
  -times, round, game, revolve, counter for occurrences"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "回り", back: "まわり
  circumference; perimeter; edge;
  surroundings; locality; neighborhood;
  rotation; circulation"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "回す", back: "まわす
  to turn; to rotate; to gyrate;
  to circulate; to send around;
  to surround;
  to put something to a new use (e.g. leftovers);  
    () (after the -masu stem of a verb) ... around (i.e. to chase someone around);
  to dial (e.g. telephone number);  
    (Godan verb with su ending) to invest;
  to gang-rape"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "回し-", back: "まわ.し-
  -times, round, game, revolve, counter for occurrences"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "回し", back: "まわし
  sumo wrestler's loincloth"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "回える", back: "か.える
  -times, round, game, revolve, counter for occurrences"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "当たる", back: "あたる
  to be hit; to strike;
  to touch; to be in contact; to be affixed;
  to be equivalent to; to be applicable; to apply to;
  to be right on the money (of a prediction, criticism, etc.);
  to be selected (in a lottery, etc.); to win;
  to be successful; to go well; to be a hit;
  to face; to confront;
  to lie (in the direction of);
  to undertake; to be assigned;
  to be stricken (by food poisoning, heat, etc.); to be afflicted;
  to be called upon (by the teacher);
  to treat (esp. harshly); to lash out at;
  to be unnecessary;
  (in baseball) to be hitting well; to be on a hitting streak;
  (in fishing) to feel a bite;
  (of fruit, etc.) to be bruised; to spoil;  
    () to feel (something) out; to probe into; to check (i.e. by comparison);
  to shave"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "当たり", back: "あたり
  hit;
  success;
  guess; prediction;
  affability; friendliness;
  sensation; touch;
  bruise (on fruit);
  situation in which a stone or chain of stones may be captured on the next move (in the game of go);
  bite (of a fish on a hook); strike;  
    (Suffix) per; each"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "当てる", back: "あてる
  to hit;
  to expose;
  to apply (e.g. patch);
  to allot; to call on someone (e.g. in class);
  to guess (an answer);
  to make a hit (e.g. in a lottery)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "当て", back: "あて
  aim; object; purpose; end;
  expectations; prospects; hopes;
  something that can be relied upon;  
    (Noun suffix) pad; guard;  
    () blow; strike"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "当に", back: "まさに
    (Usually written using kana alone)  exactly; surely; certainly;
  just (about to); on the verge (of doing or happening);
  duly; naturally"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "当にべし", back: "まさ.にべし
  hit, right, appropriate, himself"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "多い", back: "おおい
  many; numerous"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "多に", back: "まさ.に
  many, frequent, much"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "多る", back: "まさ.る
  many, frequent, much"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "交わる", back: "まじわる
  to cross; to intersect; to join; to meet;
  to associate with; to mingle with; to consort with;
  to have a sexual relationship; to copulate"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "交える", back: "まじえる
  to mix; to combine;
  to exchange (words, fire, etc.);
  to cross (e.g. swords); to join together"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "交じる", back: "まじる
  to be mixed; to be blended with; to associate with; to mingle with; to interest; to join"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "交る", back: "まじる
  to be mixed; to be blended with; to associate with; to mingle with; to interest; to join"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "交ざる", back: "まざる
  to be mixed; to be blended with; to associate with; to mingle with; to join"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "交ぜる", back: "まぜる
  to mix; to stir; to blend"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "交う", back: "かう
  to take turns; to mingle together"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "交わす", back: "かわす
  to exchange (messages, greetings, arguments, etc.);
  to intersect; to cross; to interlace;  
    () ... with one another; ... to each other"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "交す", back: "かわす
  to exchange (messages, greetings, arguments, etc.);
  to intersect; to cross; to interlace;  
    () ... with one another; ... to each other"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "近い", back: "ちかい
  near; close; short (distance)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "考える", back: "かんがえる
  to consider; to think about"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "考え", back: "かんがえ
  thinking; thought; ideas; intention"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "毎に", back: "ごとに
  one by one; each; every; at intervals of"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "光る", back: "ひかる
  to shine; to glitter; to be bright"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "言う", back: "い.う
  say"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "来る", back: "く.る, きた.る
  come, due, next, cause, become"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "来す", back: "きたす
  to cause; to induce; to bring about a result or state; to produce"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "来たす", back: "きたす
  to cause; to induce; to bring about a result or state; to produce"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "来たる", back: "きたる
  to come; to arrive; to be due to;  
    (Pre-noun adjectival) next (e.g. \"next April\"); forthcoming; coming"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "作る", back: "つくる
  to make; to produce; to manufacture; to build; to construct;
  to prepare  (Food term) ; to brew (alcohol);
  to raise; to grow; to cultivate; to train;
  to till;
  to draw up (a document); to make out; to prepare; to write;
  to create (an artistic work, etc.); to compose;
  to coin (a phrase); to organize; to organise; to establish; to found;
  to have (a child);
  to make up (one's face, etc.);
  to fabricate (an excuse, etc.);
  to form (a line, etc.);
  to set (a record);
  to commit (a sin, etc.)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "作り", back: "つく.り, -づく.り
  make, production, prepare, build"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "売る", back: "うる
  to sell"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "売れる", back: "うれる
  to sell (well);
  to be well known; to be popular; to be famous"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "谷まる", back: "きわ.まる
  valley"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "図る", back: "はかる
  to plot; to attempt; to plan; to devise; to design;
  to take in; to deceive;
  to aim for; to have something in mind;
  to refer A to B"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "走る", back: "はしる
  to run;
  to travel (movement of vehicles);
  to hurry to;
  to retreat (from battle); to take flight;
  to run away from home;
  to elope;
  to tend heavily toward"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "長い", back: "ながい
  long (distance);
  long (time); lengthy"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "明かり", back: "あかり
  light; illumination; glow; gleam;
  lamp; light"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "明るい", back: "あかるい
  bright; colourful;
  cheerful;
  familiar (with); knowledgeable (about);
  fair (e.g. politics); clean"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "明るむ", back: "あかるむ
  to brighten; to be refreshed"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "明らむ", back: "あからむ
  to become luminous at dawn (esp. the sky)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "明らか", back: "あきらか
  obvious; evident; clear; plain"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "明ける", back: "あける
  to open (a door, etc.); to unwrap (e.g. parcel, package);
  to open (for business, etc.);
  to empty; to clear out; to make space; to make room;  
    () to dawn; to grow light;
  to end"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "明け", back: "あけ
  dawn; daybreak;  
    () end; soon after something has ended;
  beginning (of a new year, month, etc.)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "明く", back: "あく
  to open (e.g. doors);
  to open (e.g. business, etc.);
  to be empty;
  to be vacant; to be available; to be free;
  to be open (e.g. neckline, etc.);
  to have been opened (of one's eyes, mouth, etc.);
  to come to an end;  
    () to open (one's eyes, mouth, etc.);  
    () to have a hole; to form a gap; to have an interval (between events)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "明くる", back: "あくる
  next; following"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "明かす", back: "あかす
  to pass (e.g. the night); to spend;
  to reveal; to divulge"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "画く", back: "えが.く
  brush-stroke, picture"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "画する", back: "かくする
  to draw (a line);
  to demarcate; to mark; to divide; to map out;
  to plan"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "画る", back: "かぎ.る, はか.る
  brush-stroke, picture"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "知る", back: "しる
  to know; to understand; to be acquainted with; to feel"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "知らせる", back: "しらせる
  to notify; to advise; to inform"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "直ちに", back: "ただちに
  at once; immediately; directly; in person; automatically"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "直す", back: "なおす
  to cure; to heal;
  to fix; to correct; to repair;  
    (Auxiliary verb) to do over again (after -masu base of verb);
  to replace; to put back as it was;
  to convert (into a different state); to transform"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "直る", back: "なおる
  to be cured; to get well; to be healed;
  to get mended; to be repaired; to be fixed"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "直き", back: "なおき
  straight; upright"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "直ぐ", back: "すぐ
    (Usually written using kana alone)  immediately; at once; directly;
  soon; before long; shortly;
  easily; without difficulty;
  right (near); nearby; just (handy)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "歩く", back: "あるく
  to walk"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "歩む", back: "あゆむ
  to walk; to go on foot"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "後ろ", back: "うしろ
  back; behind; rear"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "後れる", back: "おくれる
  to be late; to be delayed; to fall behind schedule; to be overdue"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "通る", back: "とおる
  to go by; to go past; to go along; to travel along; to pass through; to use (a road); to take (a route); to go via; to go by way of;
  to run (between); to operate (between); to connect;
  to go indoors; to go into a room; to be admitted; to be shown in; to be ushered in; to come in;
  to penetrate; to pierce; to skewer; to go through; to come through;
  to permeate; to soak into; to spread throughout;
  to carry (e.g. of a voice); to reach far;
  to be passed on (e.g. of a customer's order to the kitchen); to be relayed; to be conveyed;
  to pass (a test, a bill in the House, etc.); to be approved; to be accepted;
  to go by (a name); to be known as; to be accepted as; to have a reputation for;
  to be coherent; to be logical; to be reasonable; to be comprehensible; to be understandable; to make sense;
  to get across (e.g. of one's point); to be understood;
  to be straight (e.g. wood grain);
  
    (Archaism)  to be well-informed; to be wise;  () to do ... completely; to do ... thoroughly"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "通り", back: "とお.り, -とお.り, -どお.り
  traffic, pass through, avenue, commute, counter for letters, notes, documents, etc."),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "通す", back: "とおす
  to let pass; to overlook; to continue; to keep; to make way for; to persist in"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "通し", back: "とお.し, -どお.し
  traffic, pass through, avenue, commute, counter for letters, notes, documents, etc."),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "通う", back: "かよう
  to go back and forth; to ply between;
  to commute; to attend (school, church, etc.)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "思う", back: "おもう
  to think; to consider; to believe;
  to think (of doing); to plan (to do);
  to judge; to assess; to regard;
  to imagine; to suppose; to dream;
  to expect; to look forward to;
  to feel; to desire; to want;
  to recall; to remember"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "思く", back: "おもえら.く
  think"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "思す", back: "おぼ.す
  think"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "点ける", back: "つける
  to turn on; to switch on; to light up"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "点く", back: "つく
  to be lit (e.g. electricity comes on); to be lighted;
  to catch fire"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "点てる", back: "たてる
  to make tea (macha); to perform the tea ceremony"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "点す", back: "さ.す, とぼ.す, とも.す
  spot, point, mark, speck, decimal point"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "活きる", back: "いきる
  to live; to exist;
  to make a living; to subsist;
  to be in effect; to be in use; to function;
  to come to life; to be enlivened;
  to be safe (in baseball, go, etc.)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "活かす", back: "いかす
  to make (the best) use of; to leverage (skills, attributes, experience, etc.); to capitalise on (experience, etc);
  to let live; to keep alive;
  to revive; to resuscitate"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "活ける", back: "いける
  to arrange (flowers); to plant"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "計る", back: "はかる
  to measure; to weigh; to survey; to time (sound, gauge, estimate);
  to conjecture; to infer; to surmise"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "計らう", back: "はからう
  to manage; to arrange; to talk over; to dispose of"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "食う", back: "くう
    (Male term or language)   (Vulgar expression or word)  to eat;
  to live; to make a living; to survive;
  to bite; to sting (as insects do);
  to tease; to torment; to taunt; to make light of; to make fun of;
  to encroach on; to eat into; to consume;
  to defeat a superior; to threaten a position;
  to consume time and-or resources;
    (Colloquialism)  to receive something (usu. an unfavourable event);
    (Male term or language)   (Vulgar expression or word)  to have sexual relations with a woman, esp. for the first time"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "食らう", back: "くらう
    (Vulgar expression or word)  to eat; to drink;
  to receive (e.g. a blow)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "食べる", back: "たべる
  to eat;
  to live on (e.g. a salary); to live off; to subsist on"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "食む", back: "はむ
    (Usually written using kana alone)   (Archaism)  to eat (fodder, grass, etc.);
  to receive (a salary);
  to receive a stipend from one's lord"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "高い", back: "たかい
  high; tall;
  expensive"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "高まる", back: "たかまる
  to rise; to swell; to be promoted"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "高める", back: "たかめる
  to raise; to lift; to boost; to enhance"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "記す", back: "しる.す
  scribe, account, narrative"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "書く", back: "かく
  to write;
  to draw"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "書き", back: "-が.き
  write"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "帰る", back: "かえる
  to return; to come home; to go home; to go back;
  (of a guest, customer, etc.) to leave;
  (of a baseball player rounding the bases) to get home"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "帰す", back: "かえ.す
  homecoming, arrive at, lead to, result in"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "帰ぐ", back: "とつ.ぐ
  homecoming, arrive at, lead to, result in"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "弱い", back: "よわい
  weak; frail; delicate; tender; unskilled; weak (wine)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "弱る", back: "よわる
  to weaken; to be troubled; to be downcast; to be emaciated; to be dejected; to be perplexed; to impair"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "弱まる", back: "よわまる
  to abate; to weaken; to be emaciated; to be dejected; to be perplexed"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "弱める", back: "よわめる
  to weaken"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "強い", back: "つよ.い, こわ.い
  strong"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "強まる", back: "つよまる
  to get strong; to gain strength"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "強める", back: "つよめる
  to strengthen; to emphasize; to emphasise"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "強いる", back: "しいる
  to force; to compel; to coerce"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "教える", back: "おしえる
  to teach; to inform; to instruct"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "教わる", back: "おそわる
  to be taught"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "組む", back: "くむ
  to cross (legs or arms); to link (arms);
  to put together; to construct; to assemble; to produce (e.g. TV program);
  to braid; to plait;
  to grapple; to wrestle;
  to unite; to link up; to form an alliance;
  to set (e.g. type);
  to issue (e.g. money order)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "細い", back: "ほそい
  thin; slender; fine;
    (Slang)  unlucky (billiards slang)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "細る", back: "ほそる
  to get thin; to taper off"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "細か", back: "こまか
  small; fine; detailed; stingy"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "細かい", back: "こまかい
  small;
  fine; minute;
  minor; trivial;
  sensitive; attentive"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "黒ずむ", back: "くろずむ
  to blacken; to darken"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "黒い", back: "くろい
  black;
  dark;
  illicit; wicked; underground"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "番い", back: "つがい
    (Usually written using kana alone)  (one) pair (e.g. of birds); brace; couple;
  joint; hinge"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "答える", back: "こたえる
  to answer; to reply"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "答え", back: "こたえ
  response; reply; answer; solution"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "買う", back: "かう
  to buy; to purchase;
  to value; to have a high opinion;
  to stir; to provoke"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "遠い", back: "とおい
  far; distant"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "晴れる", back: "はれる
  to clear up; to clear away; to be sunny; to stop raining;
  to refresh (e.g. spirits);
  to be cleared (e.g. of a suspicion);
  to be dispelled; to be banished"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "晴れ", back: "はれ
  clear weather;  
    (No-adjective) public; formal;
  cleared of suspicion"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "晴れ-", back: "は.れ-
  clear up"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "晴らす", back: "はらす
  to dispel; to clear away; to refresh (oneself)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "新しい", back: "あたらしい
  new; novel; fresh; recent; latest; up-to-date; modern"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "新た", back: "あらた
  new; fresh; novel;  
    (Adverb) newly; freshly; re-"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "話す", back: "はなす
  to talk; to speak; to converse; to chat;
  to tell; to explain; to narrate; to mention; to describe; to discuss;
  to speak (a language)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "数える", back: "かぞえる
  to count; to enumerate"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "数める", back: "せ.める
  number, strength, fate, law, figures"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "数しい", back: "わずらわ.しい
  number, strength, fate, law, figures"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "楽しい", back: "たのしい
  enjoyable; fun"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "楽しむ", back: "たのしむ
  to enjoy (oneself)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "楽む", back: "たのしむ
  to enjoy (oneself)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "語る", back: "かたる
  to talk; to tell; to recite"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "語らう", back: "かたらう
  to talk; to tell; to recite; to pledge; to conspire with"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "聞く", back: "きく
  to hear;
  to listen (e.g. to music);
  to ask; to enquire; to query"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "聞こえる", back: "きこえる
  to be heard; to be audible;
  to be said to be; to be reputed"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "歌う", back: "うたう
  to sing;
  to sing (one's praises in a poem, etc.); to compose a poem; to recite a poem"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "読む", back: "よむ
  to read"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "読み", back: "よみ
  reading"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "鳴く", back: "なく
  to sing (bird);
  to bark; to purr; to make sound (animal)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "鳴る", back: "なる
  to sound; to ring; to resound; to echo; to roar; to rumble"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "鳴らす", back: "ならす
  to ring; to sound; to chime; to beat; to snort (nose)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "親しい", back: "した.しい
  parent, intimacy, relative, familiarity, dealer (cards)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "親しむ", back: "したしむ
  to be intimate with; to befriend"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "化ける", back: "ば.ける, ふ.ける
  change, take the form of, influence, enchant, delude, -ization"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "化かす", back: "ばかす
  to bewitch; to confuse; to enchant; to delude"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "化する", back: "かする
  to change into; to convert into; to transform; to be reduced; to influence; to improve (someone)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "予め", back: "あらかじめ
  beforehand; in advance; previously"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "反る", back: "そ.る, かえ.る, -かえ.る
  anti-"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "反らす", back: "そらす
  to bend; to warp; to curve"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "反す", back: "かえす
  to return (something); to restore; to put back;
  to turn over; to turn upside down; to overturn;
  to pay back; to retaliate; to reciprocate;  
    () (after the -masu stem of a verb) to repeat ...; to do ... back"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "代わる", back: "かわる
  to succeed; to relieve; to replace;
  to take the place of; to substitute for; to take over for; to represent;
  to be exchanged; to change (places with); to switch"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "代る", back: "かわる
  to succeed; to relieve; to replace;
  to take the place of; to substitute for; to take over for; to represent;
  to be exchanged; to change (places with); to switch"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "代り", back: "かわ.り, -がわ.り
  substitute, change, convert, replace, period, age, counter for decades of ages, eras, etc., generation, charge, rate, fee"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "代わり", back: "か.わり, -が.わり
  substitute, change, convert, replace, period, age, counter for decades of ages, eras, etc., generation, charge, rate, fee"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "代える", back: "かえる
  to replace;
  to exchange; to interchange;
  to substitute"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "平ら", back: "たいら
  flatness; level; smooth; calm; plain; sitting tailor fashion"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "打つ", back: "う.つ, ぶ.つ
  strike, hit, knock, pound, dozen"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "打ち-", back: "う.ち-
  strike, hit, knock, pound, dozen"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "由る", back: "よる
    (Usually written using kana alone)  to be due to; to be caused by;
  to depend on; to turn on;
  to be based on; to come from"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "仕える", back: "つかえる
  to serve; to work for; to attend"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "去る", back: "さる
  to leave; to go away;
  to pass; to elapse;
  to be distant;  
    () to send away; to drive off; to divorce;  
    () (after a -masu stem, esp. of a suru verb) ... completely;  
    (Pre-noun adjectival) last ... (e.g. \"last April\")"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "写す", back: "うつす
  to transcribe; to duplicate; to reproduce; to imitate; to trace;
  to describe;
  to film; to picture; to photograph"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "写る", back: "うつる
  to be photographed; to be projected"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "写し", back: "うつし
  copy; duplicate; facsimile; transcript"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "申す", back: "もうす
    (Humble (kenjougo) language)  to say; to be called;
    (Humble (kenjougo) language)  to do"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "申し-", back: "もう.し-
  have the honor to, sign of the monkey, 3-5PM, ninth sign of Chinese zodiac"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "号ぶ", back: "さけ.ぶ
  nickname, number, item, title, pseudonym, name, call"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "氷る", back: "こおる
  to freeze; to be frozen over; to congeal"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "全く", back: "まったく
  really; truly; entirely; completely; wholly; perfectly;
  indeed;  
    (Interjection)  (Abbreviation)  good grief (expression of exasperation)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "全て", back: "すべて
  all; the whole; entirely; in general; wholly; overall"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "安い", back: "やすい
  cheap; inexpensive;
  calm; peaceful; quiet"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "安まる", back: "やすまる
  to be rested; to feel at ease; to repose; to be relieved"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "安らか", back: "やすらか
  peaceful; tranquil; calm; restful"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "向く", back: "むく
  to face;
  to turn toward;
  to be suited to; to be fit for"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "向い", back: "むかい
  facing; opposite; across the street; other side"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "向き", back: "むき
  direction; orientation; aspect; situation; exposure; suitability; tendency"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "向ける", back: "むける
  to turn towards; to point"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "向け", back: "むけ
  intended for ...; oriented towards ...; aimed at ..."),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "向かう", back: "むかう
  to face;
  to go towards"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "向かい", back: "むかい
  facing; opposite; across the street; other side"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "向こう", back: "むこう
  opposite side; other side; opposite direction;
  over there; that way; far away; beyond;
  the other party; the other person;
  future (starting now)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "向こう-", back: "む.こう-
  yonder, facing, beyond, confront, defy, tend toward, approach"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "次ぐ", back: "つぐ
  to rank next to; to come after"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "死ぬ", back: "しぬ
  to die"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "死に-", back: "し.に-
  death, die"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "有る", back: "ある
    (Usually written using kana alone)  to be (usu. of inanimate objects); to exist; to live;
  to have;
  to be located;
  to be equipped with;
  to happen; to come about"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "守る", back: "まもる
  to protect; to guard; to defend;
  to keep (i.e. a promise); to abide (by the rules); to observe; to obey; to follow"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "守り", back: "まも.り
  guard, protect, defend, obey"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "返す", back: "かえす
  to return (something); to restore; to put back;
  to turn over; to turn upside down; to overturn;
  to pay back; to retaliate; to reciprocate;  
    () (after the -masu stem of a verb) to repeat ...; to do ... back"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "返る", back: "かえる
  to return; to come back; to go back;
  to turn over;  
    () (after the -masu stem of a verb) (to become) extremely; (to become) completely"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "曲がる", back: "まがる
  to bend; to curve; to warp; to wind; to twist;
  to turn;
  to be awry; to be askew; to be crooked"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "曲げる", back: "まげる
  to bend; to crook; to lean; to yield (a point); to depart (from a principle)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "対える", back: "こた.える
  vis-a-vis, opposite, even, equal, versus, anti-, compare"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "対い", back: "そろ.い, つれあ.い
  vis-a-vis, opposite, even, equal, versus, anti-, compare"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "対ぶ", back: "なら.ぶ
  vis-a-vis, opposite, even, equal, versus, anti-, compare"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "対う", back: "むかう
  to face;
  to go towards"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "決める", back: "きめる
  to decide; to choose; to determine; to make up one's mind; to resolve; to set one's heart on; to settle; to arrange; to set; to appoint; to fix;
  to clinch (a victory); to decide (the outcome of a match);
  to persist in doing; to go through with;
  to always do; to have made a habit of;
  to take for granted; to assume;
  to dress up; to dress to kill; to dress to the nines;
  to carry out successfully (a move in sports, a pose in dance, etc.); to succeed in doing;
    (Martial arts term)  to immobilize with a double-arm lock (in sumo, judo, etc.)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "決め", back: "-ぎ.め
  decide, fix, agree upon, appoint"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "決まる", back: "きまる
  to be decided; to be settled;
  to look good in (clothes)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "決く", back: "さ.く
  decide, fix, agree upon, appoint"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "投げる", back: "なげる
  to throw; to cast away;
  to face defeat; to give up"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "投げ", back: "なげ
  a throw; a fall"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "住む", back: "すむ
  to live (of humans); to reside; to inhabit; to dwell; to abide"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "住まう", back: "すまう
  to live; to reside; to inhabit"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "住まい", back: "すまい
  dwelling; house; residence; address"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "究める", back: "きわめる
  to carry to extremes; to go to the end of something;
  to investigate thoroughly; to master"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "助ける", back: "たすける
  to help; to save; to rescue; to give relief to; to spare (life); to reinforce; to promote; to abet"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "助かる", back: "たすかる
  to be saved; to be rescued; to survive;
  to escape harm; to be spared damage;
  to be helped; to be saved trouble"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "医やす", back: "い.やす
  doctor, medicine"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "医する", back: "いする
  to cure; to heal"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "事う", back: "つか.う
  matter, thing, fact, business, reason, possibly"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "事える", back: "つかえる
  to serve; to work for; to attend"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "定める", back: "さだめる
  to decide; to establish; to determine"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "定まる", back: "さだまる
  to become settled; to be fixed"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "定か", back: "さだか
  definite; sure"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "実る", back: "みのる
  to bear fruit; to ripen"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "表す", back: "あらわ.す
  surface, table, chart, diagram"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "表れる", back: "あらわれる
  to appear; to come in sight; to become visible; to come out; to embody; to materialize; to materialise;
  to be expressed (e.g. emotions); to become apparent (e.g. trends, effects)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "表わす", back: "あらわす
  to reveal; to show; to display;
  to express;
  to represent; to signify; to stand for;
  to make widely known"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "取る", back: "とる
  to take; to pick up; to harvest; to earn; to choose;
  to steal;
  to eat; to have (a meal);
  to remove (one's glasses, etc.);
  to compete (in sumo, cards, etc.); to play"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "取り", back: "とり
  key performer; last performer of the day;
  active partner (e.g. in judo demonstration)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "取り-", back: "と.り-
  take, fetch, take up"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "和らぐ", back: "やわらぐ
  to soften; to calm down; to be mitigated"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "和らげる", back: "やわらげる
  to soften; to moderate; to relieve"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "和む", back: "なごむ
  to be softened; to calm down"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "和やか", back: "なごやか
  mild; calm; gentle; quiet; harmonious"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "受ける", back: "うける
  to receive; to get;
  to catch (e.g. a ball);
  to be struck by (wind, waves, sunlight, etc.);
  to sustain (damage); to incur (a loss); to suffer (an injury); to feel (influence);
  to undergo (e.g. surgery); to take (a test); to accept (a challenge);
  to be given (e.g. life, talent);
  to follow; to succeed; to be descended from;
  to face (south, etc.);
  
    (Linguistic term)  to be modified by;
  to obtain (a pawned item, etc.) by paying a fee;  () to be well-received; to become popular; to go down well"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "受け", back: "うけ
  popularity; favour; favor; reception;
  defense; defence; reputation;
  agreement;
  receiver of technique (e.g. in martial arts);
    (Usually written using kana alone)   (Colloquialism)  submissive partner of a homosexual relationship"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "受かる", back: "うかる
  to pass (examination)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "委ねる", back: "ゆだねる
  to entrust to; to devote oneself to; to abandon oneself to"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "使う", back: "つかう
  to use (a thing, method, etc.); to make use of; to put to use;
  to use (a person, animal, puppet, etc.); to employ; to handle; to manage; to manipulate;
  to use (time, money, etc.); to spend; to consume;
  to use (language); to speak;
    (Idiomatic expression)  to take (one's lunch); to circulate (bad money)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "使い", back: "つかい
  errand; mission; going as envoy;
  messenger; bearer; errand boy; errand girl;
  familiar spirit;  
    () use; usage; user; trainer; tamer; charmer"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "始める", back: "はじめる
  to start; to begin; to commence; to initiate; to originate;
  to open (e.g. a store); to start up; to establish (business. etc.);  
    (Auxiliary verb) to start (doing something); to begin to ..."),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "始まる", back: "はじまる
  to begin"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "放す", back: "はなす
  to release; to let go; to free; to set free; to let loose; to turn loose;
  to add (pieces of eggplant, potato, etc.) to water, broth, etc."),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "放し", back: "-っぱな.し
  set free, release, fire, shoot, emit, banish, liberate"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "放つ", back: "はなつ
  to fire (e.g. an arrow); to hit (e.g. baseball); to break wind;
  to free; to release;
  to give off (e.g. a scent); to emit (e.g. light)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "放れる", back: "はなれる
  to leave; to get free; to cut oneself off"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "放く", back: "こく
    (Usually written using kana alone)  to let loose (e.g. a fart);
    (Usually written using kana alone)   (Vulgar expression or word)  to utter (e.g. a lie)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "放る", back: "ほう.る
  set free, release, fire, shoot, emit, banish, liberate"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "送る", back: "おくる
  to send (a thing); to dispatch; to despatch;
  to take or escort (a person somewhere); to see off (a person);
  to bid farewell (to the departed); to bury;
  to spend (time); to live one's life;
  to pass (down the line);
  to affix okurigana"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "育つ", back: "そだつ
  to be raised (e.g. child); to be brought up; to grow (up)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "育ち", back: "そだち
  breeding; growth"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "育てる", back: "そだてる
  to raise; to rear; to bring up"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "育む", back: "はぐくむ
  to raise; to rear; to bring up"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "追う", back: "おう
  to chase; to run after; to pursue;
  to follow (i.e. a set order, a trend);
  to drive out; to oust; to expel;
  to drive (i.e. a herd);
  (in passive voice) to be pressed (for time, etc.)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "味わう", back: "あじわう
  to taste; to savor; to relish"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "注ぐ", back: "そそ.ぐ, つ.ぐ
  pour, irrigate, shed (tears), flow into, concentrate on, notes, comment, annotate"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "注す", back: "さす
  to pour; to add (liquid); to serve (drinks);
  to put on (lipstick, etc.); to apply; to colour; to dye;
  to light (a fire); to burn"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "苦しい", back: "くるしい
  painful; difficult; agonizing;
  needy; tight (budget); straitened (circumstances);
  forced (smile, joke); lame (excuse); strained (interpretation);
  awkward (situation); painful (position);  
    () (after masu stem) hard to do; unpleasant"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "苦しむ", back: "くるしむ
  to suffer; to groan; to be worried"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "苦しめる", back: "くるしめる
  to torment; to harass; to inflict pain"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "苦い", back: "にがい
  bitter"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "苦る", back: "にがる
  to feel bitter; to scowl"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "具える", back: "そなえる
  to furnish; to provide for; to equip; to install;
  to have ready; to prepare for;
  to possess; to have; to be endowed with; to be armed with"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "具に", back: "つぶさに
  in detail; with great care; completely; again and again"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "幸い", back: "さいわい
  happiness; blessedness; luck; fortune; felicity;  
    (Adverb) luckily; fortunately"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "幸せ", back: "しあわせ
  happiness; good fortune; luck; blessing"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "泳ぐ", back: "およぐ
  to swim"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "発つ", back: "たつ
  to depart (on a plane, train, etc.)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "発く", back: "あば.く
  departure, discharge, publish, emit, start from, disclose, counter for gunshots"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "発る", back: "おこ.る
  departure, discharge, publish, emit, start from, disclose, counter for gunshots"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "発わす", back: "つか.わす
  departure, discharge, publish, emit, start from, disclose, counter for gunshots"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "度い", back: "-た.い
  degrees, occurrence, time, counter for occurrences"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "持つ", back: "もつ
  to hold; to carry;
  to possess"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "持ち", back: "もち
  hold; charge; keep possession; in charge;
  wear; durability; life; draw;  
    (Suffix) usage"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "持てる", back: "もてる
  to be able to possess (hold, get, etc.);
  to be well liked; to be popular; to be pampered (spoiled, doted upon, etc.); to be welcomed;
  to endure (the tests of time, the elements, etc.); to last;  
    (Pre-noun adjectival) possessed;
  possessing riches; having wealth"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "県ける", back: "か.ける
  prefecture"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "指す", back: "さす
  to point;
  to nominate; to select someone; to specify some person;
  to identify; to indicate; to point out;
  to play (shogi);
  to extend one's arm straight ahead (in dance)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "指し", back: "-さ.し
  finger, point to, indicate, put into, play (chess), measure (ruler)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "重い", back: "おもい
  heavy; weighty; massive;
  heavy (feeling); depressed; gloomy; blue; uneasy;
  slow; sluggish; lumbering; ponderous; clumsy;
  important; serious; grave;
  serious; severe; critical;
  solid; established; dignified; sensible"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "重り", back: "おもり
  weight;
  sinker (fishing)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "重なう", back: "おも.なう
  heavy, heap up, pile up, nest of boxes, -fold"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "重ねる", back: "かさねる
  to pile up; to put something on another; to heap up; to add; to repeat"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "重なる", back: "かさ.なる
  heavy, heap up, pile up, nest of boxes, -fold"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "係る", back: "かか.る
  person in charge, connection, duty, concern oneself"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "係わる", back: "かかわる
  to be affected; to be influenced;
  to be concerned with; to have to do with;
  to stick to (opinions)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "急ぐ", back: "いそぐ
  to hurry; to rush; to hasten; to make something happen sooner"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "急ぎ", back: "いそぎ
  haste; hurry; expedition; speed; dispatch"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "研ぐ", back: "とぐ
  to sharpen; to hone; to whet; to grind;
  to wash (rice);
  to scour; to polish; to burnish"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "乗る", back: "のる
  to get on (train, plane, bus, ship, etc.); to get in; to board; to take; to embark;
  to get on (e.g. a footstool); to step on; to jump on; to sit on; to mount;
  to reach; to go over; to pass;
  to follow; to stay (on track); to go with (the times, etc.);
  to take part; to participate; to join;
  to get into the swing (and sing, dance, etc.);
  to be deceived; to be taken in;
  to be carried; to be spread; to be scattered;
  to stick; to attach; to take; to go on"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "乗り", back: "のり
  riding; ride;
  spread (of paints);
  (two)-seater;
    (Usually written using kana alone)  mood (as in to pick up on and join in with someone's mood)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "乗せる", back: "のせる
  to place on (something);
  to give (someone) a ride; to give a lift; to pick up; to help on board;
  to load (luggage); to carry; to take on board;
  to send out (on the airwaves, etc.);
  to deceive; to take for a ride;
  to (sing) along with (musical accompaniment);
  to let (someone) take part;
  to excite (someone)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "待つ", back: "まつ
  to wait;
  to await; to look forward to; to anticipate;
  (usu. in negative form) to depend on; to need"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "待ち", back: "まち
  waiting; waiting time"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "負ける", back: "まける
  to lose; to be defeated;
  to succumb; to give in; to surrender; to yield;
  to be inferior to;
  to break out in a rash due to (e.g. lacquer, shaving, etc.);  
    () to reduce the price; to lower the price; to give a discount on"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "負かす", back: "まかす
  to defeat"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "負う", back: "おう
  to bear; to carry on one's back;
  to take responsibility for; to accept a duty;
  to be injured;
  to owe"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "美しい", back: "うつくしい
  beautiful; lovely"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "速い", back: "はやい
  fast; quick; hasty; brisk;
  early (in the day, etc.); premature;
  (too) soon; not yet; (too) early;
  easy; simple; quick"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "速める", back: "はやめる
  to hasten; to quicken; to expedite; to precipitate; to accelerate"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "速やか", back: "すみやか
  speedy; prompt; smooth"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "拾う", back: "ひろう
  to pick up; to find; to gather"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "進む", back: "すすむ
  to advance; to go forward;
  to precede; to go ahead (of);
  to make progress; to improve;
  to deepen; to heighten;
  to do of one's own free will"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "進める", back: "すすめる
  to advance; to promote; to hasten"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "流れる", back: "ながれる
  to stream; to flow (liquid, time, etc.); to run (ink); to be washed away"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "流れ", back: "ながれ
  stream; current; flow"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "流す", back: "ながす
  to drain; to pour; to spill; to shed (blood, tears);
  to wash away;
  to distribute (e.g. electricity over wires, music over a PA system, etc.); to circulate; to broadcast; to beam;
  to cruise (e.g. taxi);
  to float; to set adrift;
  to call off (a meeting, etc.)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "消える", back: "きえる
  to go out; to vanish; to disappear"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "消す", back: "けす
  to erase; to delete; to cross out;
  to turn off power;
  to extinguish; to put out;
    (Slang)  to bump off"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "配る", back: "くばる
  to distribute; to deliver; to deal (cards)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "起きる", back: "おきる
  to get up; to rise;
  to wake up;
  to occur (usu. of unfavourable incidents); to happen; to take place"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "起こる", back: "おこる
  to occur; to happen"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "起こす", back: "おこす
  to raise; to cause; to wake someone"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "起す", back: "おこす
  to raise; to cause; to wake someone"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "起つ", back: "たつ
  to rise up; to initiate (political) action"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "病む", back: "やむ
  to fall ill; to be ill"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "病み", back: "-や.み
  ill, sick"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "勉める", back: "つとめる
  to endeavor (endeavour); to try; to strive; to make an effort; to exert oneself; to be diligent"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "問う", back: "とう
  to ask; to question; to inquire;
  to charge (i.e. with a crime); to accuse;
  to care (about);
  without regard to (with negative verb)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "問い", back: "とい
  question; query"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "動く", back: "うごく
  to move; to stir; to shift; to shake; to swing;
  to operate; to run; to go; to work;
  to be touched; to be influenced;
  to change; to vary; to fluctuate; to waver;
  certain; factual;
  to be transferred"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "動かす", back: "うごかす
  to move; to shift; to operate; to set in motion; to mobilize; to mobilise;
  to inspire; to rouse; to move (e.g. feeling); to influence;
  to deny; to change"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "運ぶ", back: "はこぶ
  to carry; to transport; to move; to convey;
  
    (Honorific or respectful language)  to come; to go;
  to wield (a tool, etc.); to use;  () to go (well, etc.); to proceed; to progress"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "終わる", back: "おわる
  to finish; to end; to close"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "終る", back: "おわる
  to finish; to end; to close"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "終える", back: "おえる
  to finish;
  to graduate"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "終に", back: "ついに
    (Usually written using kana alone)  finally; at last;
  (with neg) in the end"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "転がる", back: "ころがる
  to roll; to tumble;
  to fall over; to roll over;
  to lie down;
  to be scattered about; to be common;
  (of a situation or outcome) to change; to turn out"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "転げる", back: "ころげる
  to roll over; to tumble; to roll about (with laughter)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "転がす", back: "ころがす
  to roll;
  to turn over; to tip over; to throw down;
  to leave;
  to buy and sell (quickly for a profit)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "転ぶ", back: "ころ.ぶ, まろ.ぶ
  revolve, turn around, change"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "転る", back: "うつ.る
  revolve, turn around, change"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "転めく", back: "くるめく
    (Archaism)  to spin; to revolve; to twirl;
  to be dizzy; to feel faint;
  to bustle about"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "商う", back: "あきなう
  to trade in (commercial goods); to deal in; to sell"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "深い", back: "ふかい
  deep; profound; thick; close"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "深まる", back: "ふかまる
  to deepen; to heighten; to intensify"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "深める", back: "ふかめる
  to deepen; to heighten; to intensify"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "悪い", back: "わる.い, にく.い, -にく.い
  bad, vice, rascal, false, evil, wrong"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "悪し", back: "あし
  evil"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "悪む", back: "にくむ
  to hate; to detest"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "宿る", back: "やどる
  to lodge; to dwell;
  to be pregnant"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "宿す", back: "やどす
  to keep (guest);
  to conceive;
  to carry (virus);
  to entrust"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "習う", back: "ならう
  to take lessons in; to be taught; to learn; to study; to get training in"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "習い", back: "ならい
  as is habit; the way life normally is"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "遊ぶ", back: "あそ.ぶ
  play"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "遊ばす", back: "あそばす
  to let one play; to leave idle;
    (Polite language)  to do"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "祭る", back: "まつる
  to deify; to enshrine;
  to pray; to worship"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "祭り", back: "まつり
  festival; feast"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "開く", back: "ひら.く, あ.く
  open, unfold, unseal"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "開き", back: "ひらき
  opening; gap;  
    (Suffix) dried and opened fish"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "開ける", back: "ひら.ける, あ.ける
  open, unfold, unseal"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "勝つ", back: "かつ
  to win; to gain victory"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "勝ち", back: "-が.ち
  victory, win, prevail, excel"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "勝る", back: "まさる
  to excel; to surpass; to exceed; to have an edge; to be superior; to outrival;
  to outweigh; to preponderate"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "勝れる", back: "すぐれる
  to surpass; to outstrip; to excel"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "集まる", back: "あつまる
  to gather; to collect; to assemble"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "集める", back: "あつめる
  to collect; to assemble; to gather"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "集う", back: "つどう
  to meet; to assemble; to congregate"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "着る", back: "きる
  to wear (in modern Japanese, from the shoulders down); to put on;
  to bear (guilt, etc.)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "着せる", back: "きせる
  to put clothes on (someone);
  to plate; to gild; to veneer;
  to accuse (of some crime); to give (a bad name)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "着せ", back: "-き.せ
  don, arrive, wear, counter for suits of clothing"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "着く", back: "つ.く
  don, arrive, wear, counter for suits of clothing"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "着ける", back: "つける
  to attach; to join; to add; to append; to affix; to stick; to glue; to fasten; to sew on; to apply (ointment);
  to furnish (a house with);
  to wear; to put on;
  to keep a diary; to make an entry;
  to appraise; to set (a price);
  to bring alongside;
  to place (under guard or doctor);
  to follow; to shadow;
  to load; to give (courage to);
  to keep (an eye on);
  to establish (relations or understanding);
  to turn on (light)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "落ちる", back: "おちる
  to fall down; to drop; to fall (e.g. rain); to sink (e.g. sun or moon); to fall onto (e.g. light or one's gaze); to be used in a certain place (e.g. money);
  to be omitted; to be missing;
  to decrease; to sink;
  to fail (e.g. exam or class); to lose (contest, election, etc.);
  to crash; to degenerate; to degrade; to fall behind;
  to become indecent (of a conversation);
  to be ruined; to go under;
  to fade; to come out (e.g. a stain); to come off (e.g. makeup); to be removed (e.g. illness, possessing spirit, name on a list);
  to fall (into someone's hands); to become someone's possession;
  to fall (into a trap); to fall (for a trick);
  to give in; to give up; to confess; to flee;
  to fall; to be defeated; to surrender;
  to come to (in the end); to end in;
  to fall (in love, asleep, etc.);
  to swoon (judo);
  to consent; to understand;
    (Computer terminology)  to crash; to freeze;
  (of animals) to die;
  to move to the depths"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "落ち", back: "おち
  slip; omission;
  outcome; final result; the end;
    (Usually written using kana alone)  punch line (of a joke)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "落とす", back: "おとす
  to drop; to lose; to let fall; to shed (light); to cast (one's gaze); to pour in (liquid); to leave behind;
  to clean off (dirt, makeup, paint, etc.); to remove (e.g. stains or facial hair); to lose; to spend money at a certain place; to omit; to leave out; to secretly let escape;
  to lose (a match); to reject (an applicant); to fail (a course); to defeat (in an election);
  to lower (e.g. shoulders or voice); to lessen (e.g. production or body weight); to worsen (quality); to reduce (e.g. rank or popularity); to speak badly of; to make light of; to fall into straitened circumstances;
  to fall into (e.g. a dilemma or sin); to make one's own; to have one's bid accepted; to force surrender; to take (e.g. an enemy camp or castle); to forcefully convince; to press for a confession; to deal with;
    (Computer terminology)  to download; to copy from a computer to another medium;
    (Martial arts term)  to make someone swoon (judo);
  to finish a story (e.g. with the punch line);
  to finish (a period, e.g. of fasting)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "登る", back: "のぼる
  to ascend; to go up; to climb;
  to ascend (as a natural process, e.g. the sun); to rise;
  to go to (the capital);
  to be promoted;
  to add up to;
  to advance (in price);
  to swim up (a river); to sail up;
  to come up (on the agenda)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "登がる", back: "あ.がる
  ascend, climb up"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "短い", back: "みじかい
  short"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "植える", back: "うえる
  to plant; to grow"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "植わる", back: "うわる
  to be planted"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "軽い", back: "かる.い
  lightly, trifling, unimportant"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "軽やか", back: "かろ.やか
  lightly, trifling, unimportant"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "軽んじる", back: "かろんじる
  to look down on; to make light of"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "等しい", back: "ひとしい
  equal; similar; like; equivalent"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "温か", back: "あたた.か
  warm"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "温かい", back: "あたた.かい
  warm"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "温まる", back: "あたた.まる
  warm"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "温める", back: "あたた.める
  warm"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "飲む", back: "のむ
  to drink; to gulp; to swallow;
  to smoke (tobacco);
  to engulf; to overwhelm;
  to keep down; to suppress;
  to accept (e.g. demand, condition);
  to make light of; to conceal"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "飲み", back: "のみ
    (Abbreviation)  drink; drinking;
  spigot; tap (in a cask, etc.);
  stock market bucketing;
  bookmaking"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "悲しい", back: "かなしい
  sad; sorrowful"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "悲しむ", back: "かなしむ
  to be sad; to mourn for; to regret"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "歯い", back: "よわ.い
  tooth, cog"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "歯する", back: "よわい.する
  tooth, cog"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "暑い", back: "あつい
  hot (weather, etc.); warm"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "寒い", back: "さむ.い
  cold"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "想う", back: "おもう
  to think; to consider; to believe;
  to think (of doing); to plan (to do);
  to judge; to assess; to regard;
  to imagine; to suppose; to dream;
  to expect; to look forward to;
  to feel; to desire; to want;
  to recall; to remember"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "暗い", back: "くらい
    (Usually written using kana alone)  dark; gloomy;
  dark (in colour); dull;
  depressed; dispirited;
  sorrowful; bitter (as in a dark past);
  unclear; unfamiliar; unknown"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "暗む", back: "くらむ
  to be dazzled by; to be dizzied by; to be disoriented by;
  to be lost in (greed, lust, etc.);
    (Archaism)  to become dark"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "暗る", back: "くれ.る
  darkness, disappear, shade, informal, grow dark, be blinded"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "練る", back: "ねる
  to knead; to thicken into a paste (stirring over a flame);
  to polish (a plan, etc.); to refine; to elaborate; to work out;
  to train; to drill; to exercise;
  to gloss (silk); to soften; to degum;
  to tan (leather);
  to temper (steel);  
    () to walk in procession; to parade; to march"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "練り", back: "ねり
  kneading; gloss; tempering;  
    () paste (e.g. bean paste, mustard paste)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "調べる", back: "しらべる
  to examine; to investigate; to check up; to sense; to study; to inquire; to search"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "調べ", back: "しらべ
  investigation; inspection; examination;
  tune; note; melody"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "調う", back: "ととのう
  to be prepared; to be in order; to be put in order; to be arranged"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "調える", back: "ととのえる
  to put in order; to arrange; to adjust;
  to get ready; to prepare;
  to raise money"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "整える", back: "ととのえる
  to put in order; to arrange; to adjust;
  to get ready; to prepare;
  to raise money"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "整う", back: "ととのう
  to be prepared; to be in order; to be put in order; to be arranged"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "辺り", back: "あた.り, ほと.り
  environs, boundary, border, vicinity"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "欠ける", back: "かける
  to be chipped; to be damaged; to be broken;
  to be lacking; to be missing;
  to be insufficient; to be short; to be deficient; to be negligent toward;
  (of the moon) to wane; to go into eclipse"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "欠く", back: "かく
  to lack; to break; to crack; to chip"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "以て", back: "もって
  with; by;
  by means of; because; in view of"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "加える", back: "くわえる
  to append; to sum up; to add (up); to include; to increase; to inflict"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "加わる", back: "くわわる
  to be added to; to be appended;
  to join in (e.g. a group of friends); to participate;
  to increase (e.g. heat); to gain in (e.g. influence); to grow; to gather (speed);
  to be subject to (e.g. pressure)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "必ず", back: "かならず
  always; without exception; necessarily; certainly; without fail; positively; invariably"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "付ける", back: "つける
  to attach; to join; to add; to append; to affix; to stick; to glue; to fasten; to sew on; to apply (ointment);
  to furnish (a house with);
  to wear; to put on;
  to keep a diary; to make an entry;
  to appraise; to set (a price);
  to bring alongside;
  to place (under guard or doctor);
  to follow; to shadow;
  to load; to give (courage to);
  to keep (an eye on);
  to establish (relations or understanding);
  to turn on (light)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "付け", back: "つ.け, -つ.け, -づ.け
  adhere, attach, refer to, append"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "付け-", back: "つ.け-
  adhere, attach, refer to, append"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "付く", back: "つ.く, -づ.く
  adhere, attach, refer to, append"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "付き", back: "つ.き, -つ.き, -づ.き
  adhere, attach, refer to, append"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "失う", back: "うしなう
  to lose; to part with"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "失せる", back: "うせる
  to disappear; to vanish"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "未だ", back: "いま.だ, ま.だ
  un-, not yet, hitherto, still, even now, sign of the ram, 1-3PM, eighth sign of Chinese zodiac"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "司る", back: "つかさどる
  to rule; to govern; to administer"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "包む", back: "つつ.む, くる.む
  wrap, pack up, cover, conceal"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "成る", back: "なる
  
    (Usually written using kana alone)  to become; to get; to grow; to be; to reach; to attain;
  to result in; to prove to be;
  to consist of; to be composed of;
  to succeed; to be complete;
  to change into; to be exchanged for;
  to play a role;
  to be promoted (shogi);  (Godan verb with ru ending)  (Honorific or respectful language)  to do ..."),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "成す", back: "なす
  to build up; to establish;
  to form; to become (a state);
  to accomplish; to achieve; to succeed in;
  to change into;
  to do; to perform;  
    (Auxiliary verb)  (Archaism)  to intend to; to attempt; to try;
    (Archaism)  to have a child"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "共に", back: "ともに
    (Usually written using kana alone)  together; jointly;
    (Usually written using kana alone)  at the same time; with; as ...; including; along with;
    (Usually written using kana alone)  both"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "争う", back: "あらそ.う
  contend, dispute, argue"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "争でか", back: "いか.でか
  contend, dispute, argue"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "伝わる", back: "つたわる
  to be handed down; to be introduced; to be transmitted; to be circulated; to go along; to walk along"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "伝える", back: "つたえる
  to convey; to report; to transmit; to communicate; to tell; to impart; to propagate; to teach; to bequeath"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "伝う", back: "つたう
  to go along; to walk along; to follow"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "伝い", back: "-づた.い
  transmit, go along, walk along, follow, report, communicate, legend, tradition"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "好む", back: "このむ
  to like; to prefer"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "好く", back: "す.く
  fond, pleasing, like something"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "好い", back: "よ.い, い.い
  fond, pleasing, like something"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "印す", back: "しるす
    (Archaism)  to leave (a mark, trace, etc.); to print; to stamp;
  to show a sign (i.e. an omen)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "老いる", back: "おいる
  to age; to grow old"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "老ける", back: "ふける
  to age; to grow old"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "兆す", back: "きざす
  to show signs (symptoms)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "兆し", back: "きざし
  signs; omen; symptoms"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "灯す", back: "ともす
  to light; to turn on"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "改める", back: "あらためる
  to change; to alter; to revise; to replace;
  to reform; to correct; to mend; to improve;
  to examine; to check; to inspect;
  to do properly; to do formally"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "改まる", back: "あらたまる
  to be renewed;
  to stand on ceremony; to be formal;
  to take a turn for the worse"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "初め", back: "はじ.め, -ぞ.め
  first time, beginning"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "初めて", back: "はじめて
  for the first time;  
    (Adverb) only after ... is it ...; only when ... do you ..."),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "初める", back: "そめる
  to begin to"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "告げる", back: "つげる
  to inform; to tell; to ring (bell, alarm, warning, etc.)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "利く", back: "きく
  to be effective; to show effect;
  to do its work; to carry out its function well;
  to be possible to use"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "別れる", back: "わかれる
  to be divided; to part from; to separate; to bid farewell"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "別ける", back: "わける
  to divide (into); to split (into); to part; to separate; to divide up; to classify; to sort out; to divide out;
  to share; to distribute; to deal out; to dish out;
  to distinguish; to discriminate; to differentiate (between);
  to break up (a fight); to mediate;
  to call a draw; to tie;
  to push one's way through (a crowd);
  to sell"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "求める", back: "もとめる
  to want; to wish for;
  to request; to demand;
  to seek; to search for; to pursue (pleasure); to hunt (a job);
    (Polite language)  to purchase; to buy"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "労する", back: "ろうする
  to work; to labor; to labour;  
    () to put to work; to make (someone) work"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "労る", back: "いたわる
  to pity; to sympathize with; to sympathise with; to console; to be kind to;
  to tend to (e.g. an injury); to care for; to nurse"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "労ずき", back: "いた.ずき
  labor, thank for, reward for, toil, trouble"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "労れる", back: "つか.れる
  labor, thank for, reward for, toil, trouble"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "労う", back: "ねぎらう
  to thank for; for reward for"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "低い", back: "ひくい
  low (height, tone, rank, degree, cost, etc.); short"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "低める", back: "ひくめる
  to lower; to be lowered"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "低まる", back: "ひくまる
  to lower; to be lowered"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "良い", back: "よ.い, -よ.い, い.い, -い.い
  good, pleasing, skilled"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "冷たい", back: "つめ.たい
  cool, cold (beer, person), chill"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "冷える", back: "ひえる
  to grow cold (from room temperature, e.g. in refrigerator); to get chilly; to cool down"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "冷や", back: "ひや
  
    (Abbreviation)  cold water;
    (Abbreviation)  cold sake;  () cold; cool; chilled; unheated"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "冷ややか", back: "ひややか
  cold; chilly; cool;
  indifferent; cold-hearted; surly; curt; composed"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "冷やす", back: "ひやす
  to cool (from room temperature); to chill; to refrigerate;
  to calm down; to cool off; to regain one's composure; to relax;
  to be frightened (at); to be scared (of)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "冷やかす", back: "ひやかす
  to banter; to make fun of; to jeer at;
  to cool; to refrigerate"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "冷める", back: "さめる
  to become cool (e.g. from a high temperature to room temperature); to come down (fever);
  to cool down (interest); to abate; to subside; to dampen"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "冷ます", back: "さます
  to cool (e.g. from a high temperature to room temperature); to dampen; to let cool; to throw a damper on; to spoil"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "芸える", back: "う.える
  technique, art, craft, performance, acting, trick, stunt"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "努める", back: "つとめる
  to endeavor (endeavour); to try; to strive; to make an effort; to exert oneself; to be diligent"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "囲む", back: "かこむ
  to surround; to encircle"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "囲う", back: "かこう
  to enclose"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "囲い", back: "かこい
  enclosure; paling; storage"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "束ねる", back: "たば.ねる, つか.ねる
  bundle, sheaf, ream, tie in bundles, govern, manage, control"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "折る", back: "おる
  to break; to fracture; to break off; to snap off; to pick (e.g. flowers);
  to fold; to bend;
  to make (origami);
  to interrupt; to end"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "折り", back: "おり
  opportunity; chance; occasion; time;  
    () fold; pleat; crease;
  small food box (wooden or cardboard)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "折れる", back: "おれる
  to break; to be broken; to snap; to fracture;
  to be folded;
  to give in; to back down; to yield; to submit;
  to turn (a corner)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "治める", back: "おさめる
  to govern; to manage;
  to subdue"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "治まる", back: "おさまる
  to be at peace; to clamp down; to lessen (storm, terror, anger)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "治る", back: "なおる
  to be cured; to get well; to be healed;
  to get mended; to be repaired; to be fixed"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "治す", back: "なおす
  to cure; to heal;
  to fix; to correct; to repair;  
    (Auxiliary verb) to do over again (after -masu base of verb);
  to replace; to put back as it was;
  to convert (into a different state); to transform"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "参る", back: "まいる
    (Humble (kenjougo) language)  to go; to come; to call;
  to be defeated; to collapse; to die;
  to be annoyed; to be nonplussed;
  to be madly in love;
  to visit (shrine, grave)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "果たす", back: "はたす
  to accomplish; to achieve; to carry out; to fulfill; to fulfil; to realize; to execute; to perform; to do;  
    () to do ... completely; to do ... entirely"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "果す", back: "はたす
  to accomplish; to achieve; to carry out; to fulfill; to fulfil; to realize; to execute; to perform; to do;  
    () to do ... completely; to do ... entirely"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "果てる", back: "はてる
  to end; to be finished; to be exhausted; to die; to perish;  
    (Suffix) indicates an extreme has been reached"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "果て", back: "はて
  the end; the extremity; the limit; the limits; the result"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "例える", back: "たとえる
  to compare; to liken; to speak figuratively; to illustrate; to use a simile"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "周り", back: "まわり
  circumference; perimeter; edge;
  surroundings; locality; neighborhood"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "固める", back: "かためる
  to harden; to freeze; to strengthen; to solidify; to make (a fist); to tramp down (snow, dirt);
  to put together; to collect; to gather; to consolidate;
  to make secure; to stabilize; to settle down; to strengthen (belief, resolution, etc.); to establish (evidence);
  to fortify; to reinforce; to support;
  to wear for a specific purpose (armor, coat, etc.);
  to swear; to resolutely vow; to sincerely promise;
  to tie tightly; to fasten;
  to hold a bow fully drawn"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "固まる", back: "かたまる
  to harden; to solidify;
  to become firm; to become certain;
  to gather (together); to assemble; to huddle together"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "固まり", back: "かたまり
  lump; mass; bundle; clump; clod; cluster"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "固い", back: "かたい
  hard; solid; tough;
  stiff; tight; wooden; unpolished (e.g. writing);
  strong; firm (not viscous or easily moved);
  safe; steady; honest; steadfast;
  obstinate; stubborn;
  bookish; formal; stuffy"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "卒する", back: "そっする
  to die; to pass away"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "卒える", back: "おえる
  to graduate"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "卒わる", back: "おわる
  to finish; to end; to close"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "刷る", back: "する
  to print;
  to color or pattern fabric using a wooden mold"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "刷り", back: "すり
  printing"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "刷く", back: "は.く
  printing, print, brush"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "泣く", back: "なく
  to cry; to weep; to sob; to howl"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "連なる", back: "つらなる
  to extend; to stretch out; to stand in a row"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "連ねる", back: "つらねる
  to line up; to put in a row;
  to add (to a group); to accept (as a member of an organization, etc.); to join (e.g. a list);
  to link; to put together; to string together (e.g. compliments); to enumerate;
  to take along with; to bring with"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "連れる", back: "つれる
  to lead; to take (a person)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "連れ", back: "つれ
  companion; company"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "約まる", back: "つづまる
  to compress; to shrink"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "約める", back: "つづめる
  to abridge; to shorten; to economize"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "約やか", back: "つづまやか
  concise; brief;
  humble; frugal;
  modest; discrete"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "要る", back: "いる
  to need"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "変わる", back: "かわる
  to change; to be transformed; to be altered; to vary;
  to move to;
  to be different; to be uncommon; to be unusual"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "変わり", back: "かわり
  change; alteration;
  unusual state or event; accident; abnormality;
  difference; distinction"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "変える", back: "かえる
  to change; to alter; to vary; to convert; to revise; to amend; to transform"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "建てる", back: "たてる
  to build; to construct"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "建て", back: "た.て, -だ.て
  build"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "建つ", back: "たつ
  to be erected; to be built"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "省みる", back: "かえりみる
  to look back (e.g. over shoulder or at the past); to turn around; to review;
  to reflect; to reconsider;
  to consider (usu. used in negative); to concern oneself about"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "省く", back: "はぶく
  to omit; to eliminate; to curtail; to economize; to economise"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "飛ぶ", back: "とぶ
  to jump; to leap; to spring; to bound; to hop;
  to fly; to soar"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "飛ばす", back: "とばす
  to fly; to fire; to hurl; to launch;
  to skip over; to omit; to drop (e.g. stitch);
  to run or drive fast; to gallop;
  to spread a rumour (rumor); to tell a story;
  to remove; to get rid of; to transfer;
  to attack; to jeer at"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "便り", back: "たよ.り
  convenience"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "栄える", back: "さか.える, は.える
  flourish, prosperity, honor, glory, splendor"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "栄え", back: "は.え, -ば.え
  flourish, prosperity, honor, glory, splendor"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "祝う", back: "いわう
  to congratulate; to celebrate; to observe (a festival)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "浅い", back: "あさい
  shallow; superficial"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "勇む", back: "いさむ
  to be in high spirits; to be encouraged; to be lively; to cheer up"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "挙げる", back: "あげる
  to raise; to elevate;
  to do up (one's hair);
  to fly (a kite, etc.); to launch (fireworks, etc.); to surface (a submarine, etc.);
  to land (a boat);
  to show someone (into a room);
  to send someone (away);
  to enrol (one's child in school); to enroll;
  to increase (price, quality, status, etc.);
  to make (a loud sound); to raise (one's voice);
  to earn (something desirable);
  to praise;
  to give (an example, etc.); to cite;
  to summon up (all of one's energy, etc.);
  to arrest;
  to nominate;
  
    (Polite language)  to give;
  to offer up (incense, a prayer, etc.) to the gods (or Buddha, etc.);
  to bear (a child);
  to conduct (a ceremony, esp. a wedding);  () (of the tide) to come in;  
    () to vomit;  
    () 
    (Usually written using kana alone)   (Polite language)  to do for (the sake of someone else);  () to complete ...;
    (Humble (kenjougo) language)  to humbly do ..."),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "挙がる", back: "あがる
  to rise; to go up; to come up; to ascend; to be raised;
  to enter (esp. from outdoors); to come in; to go in;
  to enter (a school); to advance to the next grade;
  to get out (of water); to come ashore;
  to increase;
  to improve; to make progress;
  to be promoted; to advance;
  to be made (of profit, etc.);
  to occur (esp. of a favourable result);
  to be adequate (to cover expenses, etc.);
  to be finished; to be done; to be over;
  (of rain) to stop; to lift;
  to stop (working properly); to cut out; to give out; to die;
  to win (in a card game, etc.);
  to be arrested;
  to turn up (of evidence, etc.);
  to be spoken loudly;
  to get stage fright;
  to be offered (to the gods, etc.);
  
    (Humble (kenjougo) language)  to go; to visit;
    (Honorific or respectful language)  to eat; to drink;
  to be listed (as a candidate);
  to serve (in one's master's home);
  (in Kyoto) to go north;  () (after the -masu stem of a verb) indicates completion"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "挙る", back: "こぞる
  to assemble everything together;
  to do something as a group"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "残る", back: "のこる
  to remain; to be left"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "残す", back: "のこす
  to leave (behind, over); to bequeath; to save; to reserve"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "残う", back: "そこな.う
  remainder, leftover, balance"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "残り", back: "のこり
  remnant; residue; remaining; left-over"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "差す", back: "さす
  to shine;
  to be visible;
  to be tinged with;
  to rise (of water levels); to flow in;
  to be felt (i.e. as an emotion); to come over one;  
    () to hold up (an umbrella, etc.); to put up; to raise;
  to extend one's arm straight ahead (in dance);
  to insert; to put in;
  to wear (a sword) in one's belt; to wear at one's side; to carry under one's arm;
  to insert one's arm under an opponent's arm (in sumo);
  to pole (a boat);
  to pour; to add (liquid); to serve (drinks);
  to put on (lipstick, etc.); to apply; to colour; to dye;
  to light (a fire); to burn;
  to shut; to close; to lock; to fasten;  
    () to stop in the midst of; to leave undone"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "差し", back: "さし
  between (e.g. two people); face to face"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "殺す", back: "ころす
  to kill"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "殺し", back: "ころし
  a murder"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "殺ぐ", back: "そぐ
  to chip; to slice off; to sharpen;
  to thin down; to reduce; to weaken"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "帯びる", back: "おびる
  to wear (sword, decoration, etc.); to carry;
  to be entrusted (e.g. with a mission); to take on;
  to have a trace of; to be tinged with"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "笑う", back: "わらう
  to laugh;
  to smile;
  to sneer; to ridicule"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "笑む", back: "えむ
  to smile"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "借りる", back: "かりる
  to borrow; to have a loan;
  to rent; to hire"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "訓える", back: "おしえる
  to teach; to inform; to instruct"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "訓む", back: "よむ
  to pronounce kanji (using the native Japanese reading)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "訓ずる", back: "くんずる
  to read kanji using its native Japanese pronunciation"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "浴びる", back: "あびる
  to dash over oneself (e.g. water); to bathe; to bask in (e.g. the sun); to be flooded with (e.g. light); to shower;
  to suffer (e.g. an attack); to have abuse heaped upon; to draw criticism upon oneself"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "浴びせる", back: "あびせる
  to pour on"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "産む", back: "うむ
  to give birth; to deliver; to produce"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "産まれる", back: "うまれる
  to be born"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "産す", back: "む.す
  products, bear, give birth, yield, childbirth, native, property"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "得る", back: "え.る, う.る
  gain, get, find, earn, acquire, can, may, able to, profit, advantage, benefit"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "望む", back: "のぞむ
  to desire;
  to wish for; to expect;
  to see; to command (a view of)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "敗れる", back: "やぶれる
  to be defeated; to be unsuccessful"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "健やか", back: "すこやか
  vigorous; healthy; sound"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "清い", back: "きよい
  clear; pure; noble"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "清まる", back: "きよまる
  to be purified; to be cleansed"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "清める", back: "きよめる
  to purify; to cleanse; to exorcise"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "停める", back: "と.める
  halt, stopping"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "停まる", back: "と.まる
  halt, stopping"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "救う", back: "すくう
  to rescue from; to help out of; to save"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "唱える", back: "となえる
  to recite; to chant;
  to cry; to yell; to shout;
  to advocate; to advance; to preach; to insist"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "巣くう", back: "すくう
  to build (a nest); to nest;
  to haunt (a place); to hang out (somewhere)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "最も", back: "もっとも
  most; extremely"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "結ぶ", back: "むすぶ
  to tie; to bind; to link;
  to bear (fruit);
  to close (e.g. deal); to confirm; to conclude;
  to close tightly; to purse (e.g. lips);
  to unite (with); to ally; to join hands"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "結う", back: "ゆ.う
  tie, bind, contract, join, organize, do up hair, fasten"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "結わえる", back: "ゆわえる
  to bind; to fasten; to tie up"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "無い", back: "ない
  
    (Usually written using kana alone)  nonexistent; not being (there);
  unpossessed; unowned; not had;
  unique;
  indicates negation, inexperience, unnecessariness or impossibility;  (Auxiliary adjective) (after the ren'youkei form of an adjective) not ...;
  (after the -te form of a verb) to not be...; to have not ..."),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "費やす", back: "ついやす
  to spend; to devote; to waste"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "費える", back: "ついえる
  to use up (one's savings);
  to be wasted (time, effort, etc);
  to fall apart; to become useless;
    (Archaism)  to be wiped out (in battle);
    (Archaism)  to fall apart (one's body or health)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "象る", back: "かたどる
  to model on; to make in the shape of; to represent; to pattern after; to imitate;
  to symbolise"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "然り", back: "しかり
  yes; yea; aye; affirmative;  
    ()  (Archaism)  to be so"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "然し", back: "しかし
  however; but"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "極める", back: "きわ.める, き.める
  poles, settlement, conclusion, end, highest rank, electric poles, very, extremely, most, highly, 10**48"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "極まる", back: "きわまる
  to terminate; to reach an extreme; to take to the extreme; to be in a dilemma; to be at an end"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "極まり", back: "きまり
  rule; regulation;
  settlement; conclusion; end; agreement; arrangement;
  habit; custom; habitual way;
  countenance in front of another person; face;
    (Archaism)  love relationship between a customer and a prostitute"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "極み", back: "きわみ
  height; acme; extremity"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "極め", back: "-ぎ.め
  poles, settlement, conclusion, end, highest rank, electric poles, very, extremely, most, highly, 10**48"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "量る", back: "はかる
  to measure; to weigh; to survey; to time (sound, gauge, estimate);
  to conjecture; to infer; to surmise"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "満ちる", back: "みちる
  to be full;
  to wax (e.g. moon);
  to rise (e.g. tide);
  to mature; to expire"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "満つ", back: "みつ
  to be full;
  to wax (e.g. moon);
  to rise (e.g. tide);
  to mature; to expire"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "満たす", back: "みたす
  to satisfy; to fulfill; to appease;
  to fill (e.g. a cup); to pack;
  to reach (a certain number)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "給う", back: "たまう
    (Archaism)  to receive;
  to grant; to bestow; to award;
    (Male term or language)  semi-polite or endearing auxiliary verb indicating reception by the speaker (suffixed to the -masu stem of another verb)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "給え", back: "たまえ
  please (imperative form of an auxiliary verb, suffixed to the -masu stem of another verb)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "覚える", back: "おぼえる
  to memorize; to memorise; to commit to memory; to learn by heart; to bear in mind; to remember;
  to learn; to pick up; to acquire;
  to feel;
  to think; to regard"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "覚ます", back: "さます
  to awaken;
  to disabuse;
  to sober up"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "覚める", back: "さめる
  to wake; to wake up;
  to become sober; to sober up; to regain consciousness (e.g. after anaesthesia);
  to come to one's senses; to be disillusioned"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "覚る", back: "さとる
  to understand; to comprehend; to realize; to perceive; to sense; to discern;
  to attain enlightenment"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "散る", back: "ちる
  to fall (e.g. blossoms, leaves);
  to scatter; to be dispersed;
  to disappear; to dissolve; to break up;
  to spread; to run; to blur;
  to die a noble death"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "散らす", back: "ちらす
  to scatter; to cause a shower of;
  to disperse; to distribute; to spread;
  to resolve (a symptom, condition, etc.); to relieve; to get rid of; to cure;
  to distract; to divert;  
    () to do ... wildly (i.e. disorderly or frequently); to do ... all over the place"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "散らかす", back: "ちらかす
  to scatter around; to leave untidy"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "散らかる", back: "ちらかる
  to be in disorder; to lie scattered around"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "散らばる", back: "ちらばる
  to be scattered about"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "散ける", back: "ばらける
  to unravel"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "喜ぶ", back: "よろこぶ
  to be delighted; to be glad; to be pleased;
  to congratulate;
  to gratefully accept"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "喜ばす", back: "よろこばす
  to delight; to give pleasure"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "焼く", back: "やく
  to bake; to grill;
  to develop (photos);  
    () to suntan;
  to burn (in flames, down, CD, DVD, etc.); to scorch;
  to be jealous; to be envious"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "焼き", back: "やき
  cooking, esp. frying or stir-frying; heating;
  tempering;  
    (Noun suffix) -ware"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "焼き-", back: "や.き-
  bake, burning"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "焼ける", back: "やける
  to burn; to be roasted; to be heated; to be sunburnt; to fade (in the sun); to glow red (i.e. of the sky at sunset);
  to be jealous; to be envious"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "貯める", back: "ためる
  to save (i.e. in a bank)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "貯える", back: "たくわえる
  to store; to lay in stock;
  to have a beard; to grow a beard"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "戦う", back: "たたかう
  to fight; to battle; to combat; to struggle against; to wage war; to engage in contest"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "戦く", back: "おのの.く, わなな.く
  war, battle, match"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "戦ぐ", back: "そよぐ
  to rustle; to stir; to flutter"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "続く", back: "つづく
  to continue; to last; to go on;
  to be unbroken;
  to occur again and again;
  to lead to; to connect to"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "続ける", back: "つづける
  to continue; to keep up; to keep on"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "続ない", back: "つぐ.ない
  continue, series, sequel"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "置く", back: "おく
  to put; to place;
  to leave (behind);
    (Usually written using kana alone)  to do something in advance (usu. following te-form verb)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "置き", back: "-お.き
  placement, put, set, deposit, leave behind, keep, employ, pawn"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "試みる", back: "こころみる
  to try; to test"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "試す", back: "ためす
  to attempt; to test; to try out"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "働く", back: "はたらく
  to work; to labor; to labour;
  to function; to operate; to be effective; to work (i.e. ... works); to come into play;
  to commit (e.g. a crime); to perpetrate; to do; to act; to practise; to practice;
    (Linguistic term)  to be conjugated"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "辞める", back: "やめる
  to resign; to retire; to quit; to leave (one's job, etc.)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "辞む", back: "いな.む
  resign, word, term, expression"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "愛しい", back: "いとしい
  lovely; dear; beloved; darling"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "愛でる", back: "めでる
  to love; to admire"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "愛しむ", back: "おしむ
  to be frugal; to be sparing;
  to value; to hold dear;
  to regret (e.g. a loss); to feel sorry (for);
  to be unwilling; to be reluctant"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "照る", back: "てる
  to shine;
  to look slightly upward (of a noh mask; indicating joy, etc.)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "照らす", back: "てらす
  to shine on; to illuminate"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "照れる", back: "てれる
  to be shy; to be bashful; to feel awkward; to feel embarrassed"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "選ぶ", back: "えらぶ
  to choose; to select"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "関わる", back: "かかわる
  to be affected; to be influenced;
  to be concerned with; to have to do with;
  to stick to (opinions)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "説く", back: "とく
  to explain; to advocate; to preach; to persuade"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "静か", back: "しずか
  quiet; peaceful"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "静まる", back: "しずまる
  to quieten down; to calm down; to subside; to die down; to abate; to be suppressed"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "静める", back: "しずめる
  to appease; to suppress; to calm"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "漁る", back: "あさ.る
  fishing, fishery"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "賞める", back: "ほめる
  to praise; to admire; to speak well"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "熱い", back: "あつい
  hot (thing)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "養う", back: "やしなう
  to rear; to maintain; to support (e.g. family); to cultivate"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "積む", back: "つむ
  to pile up; to stack; to load (car, ship, etc.); to pack"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "積み", back: "-づ.み
  volume, product (x*y), acreage, contents, pile up, stack, load, amass"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "積もる", back: "つもる
  to pile up; to accumulate;
  to estimate"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "積もり", back: "つもり
    (Usually written using kana alone)  intention; plan;
  conviction; belief"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "録す", back: "しる.す
  record"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "録る", back: "とる
  to take (a photo);
  to record (video, audio, etc.); to make (a film)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "験す", back: "ためす
  to attempt; to test; to try out"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "観る", back: "みる
  to see; to look; to watch; to view; to observe;
  to look over; to look on; to assess; to examine; to judge;
    (Usually written using kana alone)  to look after; to keep an eye on; to take care of;
  to view (e.g. flowers, movie);
    (Usually written using kana alone)  to try;
    (Usually written using kana alone)  to see that...; to find that..."),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "観す", back: "しめ.す
  outlook, look, appearance, condition, view"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "類い", back: "たぐい
  kind; sort; type;
  equal; match; peer"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "願う", back: "ねがう
  to desire; to wish; to hope;
  to beg; to request; to implore; to pray;  
    (Auxiliary verb) to have something done for oneself"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "競う", back: "きそう
  to compete with;
  to emulate"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "競る", back: "せる
  to compete;
  to bid;
  to sell at auction"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "競べる", back: "くらべる
  to compare; to make a comparison;
  to compete; to vie"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "久しい", back: "ひさしい
  long; long-continued; old (story)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "支える", back: "ささ.える, つか.える
  branch, support, sustain, branch radical (no. 65)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "支う", back: "かう
  to support or prop up"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "比べる", back: "くらべる
  to compare; to make a comparison;
  to compete; to vie"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "示す", back: "しめす
  to denote; to show; to point out; to indicate; to exemplify"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "可き", back: "べき
    (Usually written using kana alone)  should (suf. to verbs); must; that one ought to; to be done;
  (passive ending) -able"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "可し", back: "べし
  shall; should; must"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "旧い", back: "ふるい
  old (not person); aged; ancient; antiquated; stale; threadbare; outmoded; obsolete article"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "弁える", back: "わきまえる
  to know (right from wrong); to discern; to discriminate; to understand; to bear in mind"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "弁ける", back: "わ.ける
  valve, petal, braid, speech, dialect, discrimination, dispose of, distinguish"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "弁う", back: "あらそ.う
  valve, petal, braid, speech, dialect, discrimination, dispose of, distinguish"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "圧す", back: "お.す, へ.す
  pressure, push, overwhelm, oppress, dominate"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "圧える", back: "おさ.える
  pressure, push, overwhelm, oppress, dominate"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "圧さえる", back: "お.さえる
  pressure, push, overwhelm, oppress, dominate"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "永い", back: "ながい
  long (time); lengthy"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "犯す", back: "おかす
  to commit (e.g. crime); to perpetrate;
  to transgress; to contravene;
  to violate; to ravish; to rape; to deflower"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "在る", back: "ある
    (Usually written using kana alone)  to be (usu. of inanimate objects); to exist; to live;
  to have;
  to be located;
  to be equipped with;
  to happen; to come about"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "団い", back: "まる.い
  group, association"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "任せる", back: "まかせる
  to entrust (e.g. a task) to another; to leave to;
  to passively leave to someone else's facilities;
  to leave to take its natural course;
  to continue (something) in a natural fashion (without particular aim);
  to rely fully on one's (full strength, great ability, long time taken) to get something done"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "任す", back: "まかす
  to entrust; to leave to a person"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "再び", back: "ふたたび
  again; once more; a second time"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "因る", back: "よる
    (Usually written using kana alone)  to be due to; to be caused by;
  to depend on; to turn on;
  to be based on; to come from"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "因む", back: "ちなむ
  to be associated (with); to be connected (with)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "判る", back: "わかる
  to be understood; to be comprehended; to be grasped;
  to become clear; to be known; to be discovered; to be realized; to be realised; to be found out"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "応る", back: "あた.る
  apply, answer, yes, OK, reply, accept"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "応える", back: "こたえる
  to respond; to live up to; to reward;
  to take its toll; to strike home; to have an effect on; to be hard on someone (e.g. heat, cold, work, illness, etc.); to be a strain"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "防ぐ", back: "ふせぐ
  to defend (against); to protect; to prevent"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "述べる", back: "のべる
  to state; to express; to mention"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "余る", back: "あまる
  to remain; to be left over; to be in excess; to be too many"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "余り", back: "あま.り, あんま.り
  too much, myself, surplus, other, remainder"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "余す", back: "あます
  to save; to leave over; to spare"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "均す", back: "ならす
  to make even; to make smooth; to make level;
  to average"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "志す", back: "こころざす
  to plan; to intend; to aspire to; to set aims (sights on)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "似る", back: "にる
  to resemble; to look like; to take after;
  to be similar (in status, condition, etc.); to be close; to be alike; to be like"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "災い", back: "わざわい
  calamity; catastrophe"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "快い", back: "こころよい
  pleasant; agreeable"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "序で", back: "ついで
  opportunity; occasion"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "武し", back: "たけし
  brave"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "退く", back: "しりぞ.く, ひ.く, の.く, ど.く
  retreat, withdraw, retire, resign, repel, expel, reject"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "退ける", back: "しりぞ.ける, の.ける
  retreat, withdraw, retire, resign, repel, expel, reject"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "非ず", back: "あらず
    (Archaism)  it is not so;
  no; never mind"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "効く", back: "きく
  to be effective; to show effect;
  to do its work; to carry out its function well;
  to be possible to use"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "効う", back: "なら.う
  merit, efficacy, efficiency, benefit"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "易しい", back: "やさしい
  easy; plain; simple"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "易い", back: "やすい
  easy"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "逆さ", back: "さかさ
  reverse; inversion; upside down"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "逆らう", back: "さからう
  to go against; to oppose; to disobey; to defy"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "承る", back: "うけたまわる
    (Humble (kenjougo) language)  to hear; to be told; to know;
  to receive (order); to undertake; to comply; to take (a reservation, etc.)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "承ける", back: "うける
  to receive; to get;
  to catch (e.g. a ball);
  to be struck by (wind, waves, sunlight, etc.);
  to sustain (damage); to incur (a loss); to suffer (an injury); to feel (influence);
  to undergo (e.g. surgery); to take (a test); to accept (a challenge);
  to be given (e.g. life, talent);
  to follow; to succeed; to be descended from;
  to face (south, etc.);
  
    (Linguistic term)  to be modified by;
  to obtain (a pawned item, etc.) by paying a fee;  () to be well-received; to become popular; to go down well"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "承げる", back: "ささ.げる
  acquiesce, hear, listen to, be informed, receive"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "承める", back: "とど.める
  acquiesce, hear, listen to, be informed, receive"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "承らす", back: "こ.らす
  acquiesce, hear, listen to, be informed, receive"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "承で", back: "つい.で
  acquiesce, hear, listen to, be informed, receive"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "承う", back: "すく.う
  acquiesce, hear, listen to, be informed, receive"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "居る", back: "い.る, お.る
  reside, to be, exist, live with"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "招く", back: "まねく
  to invite; to ask;
  to beckon; to wave someone in; to gesture to;
  to call in; to send for; to summon;
  to bring on oneself; to cause; to incur; to lead to; to result in"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "迷う", back: "まよう
  to lose one's way;
  to waver; to hesitate; to be of two minds over; to be puzzled; to be perplexed;
  to give into temptation; to lose control of oneself;
  to turn in one's grave"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "舎る", back: "やど.る
  cottage, inn, hut, house, mansion"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "往く", back: "い.く, ゆ.く
  journey, travel, chase away, let go, going, before, formerly"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "往に", back: "さき.に
  journey, travel, chase away, let go, going, before, formerly"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "肥える", back: "こえる
  to grow fat; to gain weight; to put on weight;
  to grow fertile;
  to be refined (palate); to be discerning (eye, ear);
  to become rich; to become successful"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "肥やす", back: "こやす
  to fertilize; to fertilise; to manure; to enrich"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "肥やし", back: "こやし
  manure; night soil; dung; fertiliser; fertilizer"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "肥る", back: "ふとる
  to grow fat (stout, plump); to become fat; to gain weight"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "保つ", back: "たもつ
  to keep; to preserve; to hold; to retain; to maintain; to support; to sustain; to last; to endure; to keep well  (Food term) ; to wear well; to be durable"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "独り", back: "ひとり
  one person;
  alone; unmarried; solitary"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "限る", back: "かぎる
  to restrict; to limit; to confine;  
    () to be restricted to; to be limited to; to be confined to"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "限り", back: "かぎ.り, -かぎ.り
  limit, restrict, to best of ability"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "造る", back: "つくる
  to make; to produce; to manufacture; to build; to construct;
  to prepare  (Food term) ; to brew (alcohol);
  to raise; to grow; to cultivate; to train;
  to till;
  to draw up (a document); to make out; to prepare; to write;
  to create (an artistic work, etc.); to compose;
  to coin (a phrase); to organize; to organise; to establish; to found;
  to have (a child);
  to make up (one's face, etc.);
  to fabricate (an excuse, etc.);
  to form (a line, etc.);
  to set (a record);
  to commit (a sin, etc.)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "造り", back: "つく.り, -づく.り
  create, make, structure, physique"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "故い", back: "ふるい
  old (not person); aged; ancient; antiquated; stale; threadbare; outmoded; obsolete article"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "則る", back: "のっとる
  to conform to; to be in accordance with; to follow (rule, tradition, example, etc.)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "厚い", back: "あつい
  thick; deep; heavy;
  kind; cordial; hospitable; warm; faithful;
  abundant"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "容れる", back: "いれる
  to put in; to let in; to take in; to bring in; to insert; to set (a jewel, etc.); to ink in (e.g. a tattoo);
  to admit; to accept; to employ; to hire;
  to accept; to comply; to grant; to adopt (a policy, etc.); to take (advice, etc.); to listen to; to pay attention to;
  to include;
  to pay (one's rent, etc.);
  to cast (a vote);
  to make (tea, coffee, etc.);
  to turn on (a switch, etc.);
  to send (a fax); to call"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "能く", back: "よく
    (Usually written using kana alone)  nicely; properly; well; skillfully;
  frequently; often"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "師う", back: "なら.う
  expert, teacher, master, model, exemplar, army (incl. counter), war"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "破る", back: "やぶる
  to tear; to violate; to defeat; to smash; to destroy; to break (e.g. password)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "破れる", back: "やぶれる
  to get torn; to wear out"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "修める", back: "おさめる
  to study; to complete (a course); to cultivate; to master;
  to order (one's life);
  to repair (a fault one has committed)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "修まる", back: "おさまる
  to govern oneself; to conduct oneself well"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "益す", back: "ま.す
  benefit, gain, profit, advantage"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "留める", back: "と.める, とど.める
  detain, fasten, halt, stop"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "留まる", back: "と.まる, とど.まる
  detain, fasten, halt, stop"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "耕す", back: "たがやす
  to till; to plow; to plough; to cultivate"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "経る", back: "へる
  to pass; to elapse; to experience"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "経つ", back: "たつ
  to pass; to lapse"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "現れる", back: "あらわれる
  to appear; to come in sight; to become visible; to come out; to embody; to materialize; to materialise;
  to be expressed (e.g. emotions); to become apparent (e.g. trends, effects)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "現す", back: "あらわす
  to reveal; to show; to display;
  to express;
  to represent; to signify; to stand for;
  to make widely known"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "現つ", back: "うつつ
  reality; consciousness"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "務める", back: "つとめる
  to work (for); to be employed (at); to serve (in);
  to serve (as); to act (as); to fill (the position of); to play the role (of);
  to conduct a religious service"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "設ける", back: "もうける
  to create; to establish"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "情け", back: "なさけ
  pity; sympathy; compassion;
  affection"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "過ぎる", back: "す.ぎる, -す.ぎる, よ.ぎる
  overdo, exceed, go beyond, error"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "過ぎ", back: "すぎ
  past; after;
  too (much); over (e.g. eating)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "過ごす", back: "すごす
  to pass (time); to spend;
  to overdo (esp. of one's alcohol consumption); to drink (alcohol);
  
    (Archaism)  to take care of; to support;  () to overdo; to do too much;
  to ... without acting on it"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "過つ", back: "あやまつ
  to err"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "過ち", back: "あやまち
  fault; error; indiscretion; faux pas"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "断つ", back: "たつ
  to sever; to cut off; to suppress; to abstain (from)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "断る", back: "ことわる
  to refuse; to reject; to dismiss; to turn down; to decline;
  to inform; to give notice; to tell in advance;
  to ask leave; to excuse oneself (from)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "断める", back: "さだ.める
  severance, decline, refuse, apologize, warn, dismiss, prohibit, decision, judgement, cutting"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "率いる", back: "ひきいる
  to lead; to spearhead (a group); to command (troops)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "張る", back: "は.る
  lengthen, counter for bows & stringed instruments, stretch, spread, put up (tent)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "張り", back: "-は.り, -ば.り
  lengthen, counter for bows & stringed instruments, stretch, spread, put up (tent)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "移る", back: "うつる
  to move (house); to transfer (department);
  to change the target of interest or concern;
  to elapse (passage of time);
  to be permeated by a colour or scent;
    (Usually written using kana alone)  to be infected; to be contagious; to spread (as in fire)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "移す", back: "うつす
  to change; to swap; to substitute; to transfer;
  to change the object of one's interest or focus;
  to spend or take time;
  to infect;
  to permeate something with the smell or colour of something;
  to move on to the next or different stage of (a plan, etc.)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "接ぐ", back: "つ.ぐ
  touch, contact, adjoin, piece together"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "授ける", back: "さずける
  to grant; to award; to teach"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "授かる", back: "さずかる
  to be awarded (e.g. a prize); to be given an award; to receive (e.g. a title);
  to be gifted or endowed (e.g. with a talent);
  to be blessed (e.g. with a child);
  to be initiated (e.g. into a secret)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "責める", back: "せめる
  to condemn; to blame; to criticize; to criticise; to reproach; to accuse;
  to urge; to press; to pester;
  to torture; to torment; to persecute;
  to break in (a horse)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "採る", back: "とる
  to adopt (measure, proposal);
  to pick (e.g. fruit); to catch (e.g. insects); to take (e.g. a sample);
  to assume (attitude);
  to take on (i.e. hire); to engage"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "寄る", back: "よる
  to visit; to drop in; to approach"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "寄り", back: "より
  pushing back one's opponent while locked in close quarters (sumo);  
    (Suffix) having a tendency towards; being close to"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "寄せる", back: "よせる
  to come near; to let someone approach;
  to collect; to gather; to receive;
  to add;
  to put aside"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "険しい", back: "けわしい
  precipitous; rugged; inaccessible; impregnable; steep;
  grim; severe; stern"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "許す", back: "ゆるす
  to permit; to allow; to approve;
  to exempt (from fine); to excuse (from); to pardon; to forgive; to release; to let off;
  to confide in;
  to give up; to yield"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "略す", back: "りゃくす
  to abbreviate; to omit;
  to take; to capture"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "略める", back: "おさ.める
  abbreviation, omission, outline, shorten, capture, plunder"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "略る", back: "はか.る
  abbreviation, omission, outline, shorten, capture, plunder"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "略く", back: "はぶ.く
  abbreviation, omission, outline, shorten, capture, plunder"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "略する", back: "りゃくする
  to abbreviate; to omit;
  to take; to capture"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "混じる", back: "ま.じる
  mix, blend, confuse"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "混じり", back: "まじり
  mixed; mingled"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "混ざる", back: "まざる
  to be mixed; to be blended with; to associate with; to mingle with; to join"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "混ぜる", back: "まぜる
  to mix; to stir; to blend"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "混む", back: "こむ
  to be crowded; to be packed;
  to be complex"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "貧しい", back: "まずしい
  poor; needy"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "統べる", back: "すべる
  to control; to supervise"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "統る", back: "ほび.る
  overall, relationship, ruling, governing"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "報いる", back: "むくいる
  to reward; to recompense; to repay"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "提げる", back: "さ.げる
  propose, take along, carry in hand"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "減る", back: "へる
  to decrease (in size or number); to diminish; to abate"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "減らす", back: "へらす
  to abate; to decrease; to diminish; to shorten"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "検べる", back: "しら.べる
  examination, investigate"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "営む", back: "いとなむ
  to carry on (e.g. in ceremony); to run a business"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "営み", back: "いとなみ
  work; life"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "備える", back: "そなえる
  to furnish; to provide for; to equip; to install;
  to have ready; to prepare for;
  to possess; to have; to be endowed with; to be armed with"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "備わる", back: "そなわる
  to be furnished with; to be endowed with;
  to be among; to be one of; to be possessed of"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "備に", back: "つぶさに
  in detail; with great care; completely; again and again"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "富む", back: "とむ
  to be rich; to become rich"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "測る", back: "はかる
  to measure; to weigh; to survey; to time (sound, gauge, estimate);
  to conjecture; to infer; to surmise"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "絶える", back: "たえる
  to die out; to peter out; to become extinct;
  to cease; to be stopped; to be discontinued; to be cut off"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "絶やす", back: "たやす
  to exterminate; to eradicate;
  to let (fire) go out"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "絶つ", back: "たつ
  to sever; to cut off; to suppress; to abstain (from)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "貸す", back: "かす
  to lend; to loan;
  to rent out; to hire out"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "貸し-", back: "か.し-
  lend"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "解く", back: "と.く, ほど.く
  unravel, notes, key, explanation, understanding, untie, undo, solve, answer, cancel, absolve, explain, minute"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "解かす", back: "とかす
  to comb out;
  to melt"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "解ける", back: "と.ける, ほど.ける
  unravel, notes, key, explanation, understanding, untie, undo, solve, answer, cancel, absolve, explain, minute"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "解る", back: "わかる
  to be understood; to be comprehended; to be grasped;
  to become clear; to be known; to be discovered; to be realized; to be realised; to be found out"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "勢い", back: "いきおい
  force; vigor; vigour; energy; spirit; life;
  influence; authority; power; might;
  impetus; momentum; course (of events);  
    (Adverbial noun) naturally; necessarily"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "準じる", back: "じゅんじる
  to follow; to conform; to apply to"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "準ずる", back: "じゅんずる
  to apply correspondingly; to correspond to; to be proportionate to; to conform to"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "準える", back: "なぞら.える
  semi-, correspond to, proportionate to, conform, imitate"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "準しい", back: "ひと.しい
  semi-, correspond to, proportionate to, conform, imitate"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "適う", back: "かなう
  to come true (wish);
    (Usually written using kana alone)  to be suited;
  to match (implies competition); to rival; to bear (e.g. I can't bear the heat)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "豊か", back: "ゆたか
  abundant; wealthy; plentiful; rich; affluent"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "損なう", back: "そこなう
  to harm; to hurt; to injure; to damage; to fail in doing"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "損う", back: "そこなう
  to harm; to hurt; to injure; to damage; to fail in doing"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "損ねる", back: "そこねる
  to harm; to hurt; to injure; to wreck;  
    (Auxiliary verb) to miss out, despite wanting to do"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "夢みる", back: "ゆめ.みる
  dream, vision, illusion"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "夢い", back: "くら.い
  dream, vision, illusion"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "預ける", back: "あずける
  to give into custody; to leave (a child) in the care of; to entrust; to deposit;
  to lean on; to put one's weight on"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "預かる", back: "あずかる
  to look after; to take care of; to keep; to hold on to; to keep in custody;
  to take charge of; to be entrusted with; to receive on deposit;
  to reserve (judgment); to leave undecided"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "群れる", back: "むれる
  to crowd; to flock; to swarm"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "群れ", back: "むれ
  group; crowd; flock; herd; bevy; school; swarm; cluster (e.g. of stars); clump; pack (e.g. of dogs)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "群がる", back: "むらがる
  to swarm; to gather"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "飼う", back: "かう
  to keep (a pet or other animal); to raise; to have; to own; to feed"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "総べて", back: "すべて
  all; the whole; entirely; in general; wholly; overall"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "総て", back: "すべて
  all; the whole; entirely; in general; wholly; overall"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "増す", back: "ます
  to increase; to grow"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "増し", back: "まし
  better; less objectionable; preferable;  
    (Noun suffix) more; increase; extra;  
    (Noun)  (Archaism)  increase; growth"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "増える", back: "ふえる
  to increase; to multiply"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "増やす", back: "ふやす
  to increase; to add to; to augment"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "構える", back: "かまえる
  to set up (e.g. a building);
  to prepare in advance (e.g. a meal); to prepare to use something (e.g. a camera);
  to plan; to scheme;
  to fabricate in order to deceive;
  to stiffen; to become formal"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "構う", back: "かまう
  to mind; to care about; to be concerned about;
  to care for; to look after;
  to prepare for;
  to interfere with; to meddle in;
  to tease"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "態と", back: "わざと
  on purpose"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "雑える", back: "まじえる
  to mix; to combine;
  to exchange (words, fire, etc.);
  to cross (e.g. swords); to join together"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "雑る", back: "まじ.る
  miscellaneous"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "慣れる", back: "なれる
  to grow accustomed (to); to get too familiar with; to get used (to);
  to become domesticated; to become tame"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "慣らす", back: "ならす
  to accustom"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "酸い", back: "すい
  sour; acid"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "確か", back: "たしか
  certain; sure; definite;  
    (Adverb) if I'm not mistaken; if I remember correctly"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "確かめる", back: "たしかめる
  to ascertain; to check; to make sure"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "導く", back: "みちびく
  to guide; to lead; to show the way; to conduct;
  to derive; to deduce"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "質す", back: "ただす
  to enquire of someone about something (inquire); to question"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "編む", back: "あむ
  to knit; to plait; to braid;
  to compile (anthology, dictionary, etc.); to edit"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "編み", back: "-あ.み
  compilation, knit, plait, braid, twist, editing, completed poem, part of a book"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "暴く", back: "あばく
  to disclose; to divulge; to expose"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "暴れる", back: "あばれる
  to act violently; to rage; to struggle; to be riotous"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "賛ける", back: "たす.ける
  approve, praise, title or inscription on picture, assist, agree with"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "賛える", back: "たた.える
  approve, praise, title or inscription on picture, assist, agree with"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "敵う", back: "かなう
  to come true (wish);
    (Usually written using kana alone)  to be suited;
  to match (implies competition); to rival; to bear (e.g. I can't bear the heat)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "潔い", back: "いさぎよい
  manly; sportsmanlike; gracious; gallant; resolute;
  pure (heart, actions, etc.); upright; blameless;
    (Archaism)  unsullied (e.g. scenery or object); pure; clean"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "興る", back: "おこる
  to rise; to flourish"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "興す", back: "おこす
  to revive; to retrieve (fortunes); to raise up"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "築く", back: "きずく
  to build; to pile up; to amass"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "燃える", back: "もえる
  to burn; to get fired up"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "燃やす", back: "もやす
  to burn"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "燃す", back: "も.す
  burn, blaze, glow"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "謝る", back: "あやまる
  to apologize; to apologise"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "織る", back: "おる
  to weave"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "織り", back: "おり
  weave; weaving; woven item"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "識る", back: "しる
  to know; to understand; to be acquainted with; to feel"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "識す", back: "しるす
  to write down; to note; to jot down;
  to remember"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "護る", back: "まもる
  to protect; to guard; to defend;
  to keep (i.e. a promise); to abide (by the rules); to observe; to obey; to follow"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "亡い", back: "ない
  dead"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "亡き-", back: "な.き-
  deceased, the late, dying, perish"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "亡びる", back: "ほろびる
  to be ruined; to go under; to perish; to be destroyed"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "亡ぶ", back: "ほろぶ
  to be ruined; to go under; to perish; to be destroyed"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "亡ぼす", back: "ほろぼす
  to destroy; to overthrow; to wreck; to ruin"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "干す", back: "ほす
  to air; to dry; to desiccate;
  to drain (off);
  to drink up;
  to deprive of a role, job, etc. (usu. in the passive)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "干し-", back: "ほ.し-
  dry, parch"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "干し", back: "ほし
  drying; dried"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "干る", back: "ひる
  to dry"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "収める", back: "おさめる
  to dedicate; to make an offering; to pay (fees);
  to supply;
  to store;
  to finish; to bring to a close;
  to restore (something to its place);
  to achieve (e.g. a result)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "収まる", back: "おさまる
  to be in one's place; to be installed; to settle into;
  to be delivered; to be obtained; to be paid;
  to be settled; to be sorted out;
  to lessen (e.g. of storms, pain); to calm down;
  to be fit tightly into (e.g. a frame); to be sheathed (in a scabbard)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "処る", back: "お.る
  dispose, manage, deal with, sentence, condemn, act, behave, place"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "幼い", back: "おさな.い
  infancy, childhood"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "危ない", back: "あぶない
  dangerous; risky; hazardous; perilous; precarious;
  in danger; in jeopardy; critical; grave; at risk;
  uncertain; unreliable; insecure; unsteady; doubtful;
  close (i.e. a close call); narrow;  
    (Interjection) look out!; watch out!"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "危うい", back: "あやうい
  dangerous; risky; hazardous; perilous; precarious;
  in danger; in jeopardy; critical; grave; at risk;
  uncertain; unreliable; insecure; unsteady; doubtful;
  close (i.e. a close call); narrow"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "危ぶむ", back: "あやぶむ
  to fear; to have misgivings; to be doubtful; to mistrust"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "至る", back: "いたる
  to arrive at (e.g. a decision); to reach (a stage); to attain;
  to lead to (a place); to get to;
    (Archaism)  to come; to arrive; to result in"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "吸う", back: "すう
  to smoke; to breathe in; to inhale;
  to suck; to sip; to slurp;
  to absorb; to soak up;
  to kiss"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "延びる", back: "のびる
  to stretch; to extend; to lengthen; to spread;
  to make progress; to grow (beard, body height);
  to grow stale (soba);
  to be straightened; to be flattened; to be smoothed;
  to be exhausted;
  to be postponed; to be prolonged"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "延べる", back: "のべる
  to lay out (a futon); to make (bed); to spread out; to stretch; to widen;
  to postpone; to extend"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "延べ", back: "のべ
  futures;
  credit (buying);
  stretching;
  total; gross"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "延ばす", back: "のばす
  to grow long (beard, hair, etc.);
  to lengthen; to extend; to stretch;
  to reach out; to hold out;
  to straighten; to smooth out;
  to spread evenly (dough, cream, etc.);
  to dilute; to thin out;
  to postpone;
  to prolong;
  to strengthen; to develop; to expand"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "乱れる", back: "みだれる
  to be disordered; to be disarranged; to be disarrayed; to be disheveled; to be dishevelled;
  to be discomposed; to be upset; to get confused; to be disturbed;
  to lapse into chaos (due to war, etc.)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "乱る", back: "みだ.る, わた.る
  riot, war, disorder, disturb"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "乱す", back: "みだす
  to throw out of order; to disarrange; to disturb"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "乱める", back: "おさ.める
  riot, war, disorder, disturb"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "我が-", back: "わ.が-
  ego, I, selfish, our, oneself"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "困る", back: "こまる
  to be troubled; to be worried; to be bothered; to be embarrassed; to be stumped"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "忘れる", back: "わすれる
  to forget; to leave carelessly; to be forgetful of; to forget about; to forget (an article)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "供える", back: "そなえる
  to offer; to sacrifice; to dedicate"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "担ぐ", back: "かつぐ
  to shoulder; to carry on one's shoulder;
  to take (someone) for a ride; to deceive; to take in"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "担う", back: "になう
  to carry on shoulder; to bear (burden); to shoulder (gun)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "若い", back: "わかい
  young"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "若しくわ", back: "も.しくわ
  young, if, perhaps, possibly, low number, immature"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "若し", back: "も.し, ごと.し
  young, if, perhaps, possibly, low number, immature"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "若しくは", back: "もしくは
  or; otherwise"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "呼ぶ", back: "よぶ
  to call out (to); to call; to invoke;
  to summon (a doctor, etc.);
  to invite;
  to designate; to name; to brand;
  to garner (support, etc.); to gather;
    (Archaism)  to take as one's wife"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "並み", back: "なみ
  average; medium; common; ordinary;
  line; row of (e.g. houses);
  mid-grade;
  same level; equal; each (e.g. month); set of (e.g. teeth)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "並べる", back: "ならべる
  to line up; to set up;
  to enumerate; to itemize"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "並ぶ", back: "ならぶ
  to line up; to stand in a line;
  to rival; to match; to equal"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "並びに", back: "ならびに
  and (also); both ... and; as well as"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "拡がる", back: "ひろがる
  to spread (out); to extend; to stretch; to reach to; to get around; to fill (e.g. a space)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "拡げる", back: "ひろげる
  to spread; to extend; to expand; to enlarge; to widen; to broaden; to unfold; to open; to unroll"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "拡める", back: "ひろ.める
  broaden, extend, expand, enlarge"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "刻む", back: "きざむ
  to mince; to cut fine; to chop up; to hash;
  to carve; to engrave; to chisel; to notch;
  to tick away (time); to record the passing moments;
  to etch (into one's mind); to remember distinctly;
    (Archaism)  to have tattooed;
    (Archaism)  to torment"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "刻み", back: "きざみ
  shredded tobacco; notch; nick"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "届ける", back: "とどける
  to deliver; to forward; to send;
  to report; to notify; to file notice (to the authorities); to give notice; to register"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "届け", back: "とどけ
  report; notification; registration"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "届く", back: "とどく
  to reach; to arrive; to get through; to get at;
  to be attentive; to pay attention;
  to be delivered; to carry (e.g. sound)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "沿う", back: "そう
  to run along; to run beside;
  to follow (a plan, etc.); to act in accordance with"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "沿い", back: "ぞい
  along"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "拝む", back: "おがむ
  to assume the posture of praying; to press the palms and fingers of both hands together; to do reverence (e.g. before a statue of the Buddha); to pay one's respects;
  to beg; to make a supplication;
    (Humble (kenjougo) language)  to see (something or someone of high status)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "垂れる", back: "た.れる
  droop, suspend, hang, slouch"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "垂らす", back: "たらす
  to dribble; to spill;
  to suspend; to hang down; to slouch; to dangle"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "垂れ", back: "た.れ, -た.れ
  droop, suspend, hang, slouch"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "垂す", back: "なんなんと.す
  droop, suspend, hang, slouch"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "映る", back: "うつる
  to be reflected; to harmonize with (harmonise); to come out (photo); to be projected"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "映す", back: "うつす
  to project; to reflect; to cast (shadow)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "映える", back: "はえる
  to shine; to look attractive; to look pretty"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "映え", back: "はえ
  glory; prosperity"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "専ら", back: "もっぱ.ら
  specialty, exclusive, mainly, solely"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "宣う", back: "のたまう
  to say; to be pleased to say (hint of sarcasm)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "背く", back: "そむく
  to run counter to; to go against; to disobey; to infringe"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "背ける", back: "そむける
  to turn one's face away; to avert one's eyes"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "染める", back: "そめる
  to dye; to colour; to color"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "染め", back: "そめ
  dyeing; printing"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "染まる", back: "そまる
  to be dyed;
  to be tainted; to be infected; to be stained; to be steeped"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "染みる", back: "し.みる, -じ.みる
  dye, color, paint, stain, print"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "染み", back: "しみ
  stain; spot"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "巻く", back: "まく
  to wind; to coil; to roll"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "巻き", back: "まき
  roll (e.g. of cloth);
  winding;
  volume (of book)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "看る", back: "みる
  to look after (often medically); to take care of"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "奏でる", back: "かなでる
  to play an instrument (esp. string instruments)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "洗う", back: "あらう
  to wash;
  to investigate"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "紅い", back: "あかい
  red;
  Red (i.e. communist)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "討つ", back: "うつ
  to shoot (at);
  to attack; to defeat; to destroy; to avenge"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "座る", back: "すわる
  to sit; to squat;
  to assume (a position);
  to hold steady; to hold still"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "除く", back: "のぞく
  to remove; to exclude; to except"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "除け", back: "よけ
  protection; repellent"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "降りる", back: "おりる
  to descend (e.g. a mountain); to go down; to come down;
  to alight (e.g. from bus); to get off; to disembark; to dismount;
  to step down; to retire; to give up; to quit;
  to be granted; to be issued; to be given;
  to form (of frost, dew, mist, etc.);
  to be passed (from the body; i.e. of a roundworm)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "降ろす", back: "おろす
  to take down (e.g. flag); to launch (e.g. boat); to drop; to lower (e.g. ladder); to let (a person) off; to unload; to discharge;
  to drop off (a passenger from a vehicle); to let (a person) off;
  to withdraw money from an account;
  to wear (clothing) for the first time;
  to fillet (e.g. a fish)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "降る", back: "ふ.る, くだ.る
  descend, precipitate, fall, surrender"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "降り", back: "ふり
  rainfall; snowfall;
  alighting; descending"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "降す", back: "くだす
  to make (a decision); to pass (judgement, etc.); to hand down (orders, etc.);
  to let go down; to lower;
  to do oneself; to do by oneself"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "従う", back: "したがう
  to abide (by the rules); to obey; to follow; to accompany"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "従える", back: "したがえる
  to be accompanied by;
  to subdue"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "将に", back: "まさに
    (Usually written using kana alone)  exactly; surely; certainly;
  just (about to); on the verge (of doing or happening);
  duly; naturally"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "将る", back: "ひきい.る
  leader, commander, general, admiral, or, and again, soon, from now on, just about"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "秘める", back: "ひめる
  to hide; to keep to oneself"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "秘か", back: "ひそか
  secret; private; surreptitious"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "秘す", back: "かく.す
  secret, conceal"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "射る", back: "いる
  to shoot"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "射す", back: "さす
  to shine"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "射つ", back: "うつ
  to shoot (at);
  to attack; to defeat; to destroy; to avenge"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "納める", back: "おさめる
  to dedicate; to make an offering; to pay (fees);
  to supply;
  to store;
  to finish; to bring to a close;
  to restore (something to its place);
  to achieve (e.g. a result)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "納まる", back: "おさまる
  to be in one's place; to be installed; to settle into;
  to be delivered; to be obtained; to be paid;
  to be settled; to be sorted out;
  to lessen (e.g. of storms, pain); to calm down;
  to be fit tightly into (e.g. a frame); to be sheathed (in a scabbard)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "朗らか", back: "ほがらか
  brightness; cheerfulness; melodious"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "済む", back: "すむ
  to finish; to end; to be completed;
  to merely result in something less severe than expected;
  to feel at ease;
  to feel unease or guilt for troubling someone; to be sorry"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "済み", back: "-ず.み
  finish, come to an end, excusable, need not"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "済まない", back: "すまない
  
    (Usually written using kana alone)  inexcusable; unjustifiable; unpardonable;
  sorry; remorseful; apologetic; conscience-stricken; contrite;  (Expression) excuse me; (I'm) sorry; thank you"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "済ます", back: "すます
  to finish; to get it over with; to conclude;
  to settle; to pay back;
  to get along (without something); to make do with (without)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "済う", back: "すく.う
  finish, come to an end, excusable, need not"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "済す", back: "な.す
  finish, come to an end, excusable, need not"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "済る", back: "わた.る
  finish, come to an end, excusable, need not"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "視る", back: "みる
  to see; to look; to watch; to view; to observe;
  to look over; to look on; to assess; to examine; to judge;
    (Usually written using kana alone)  to look after; to keep an eye on; to take care of;
  to view (e.g. flowers, movie);
    (Usually written using kana alone)  to try;
    (Usually written using kana alone)  to see that...; to find that..."),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "訪れる", back: "おとず.れる
  call on, visit, look up, offer sympathy"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "訪ねる", back: "たずねる
  to visit"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "訪う", back: "と.う
  call on, visit, look up, offer sympathy"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "推す", back: "おす
  to infer; to conclude; to support"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "異なる", back: "ことなる
  to differ; to vary; to disagree"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "盛る", back: "も.る, さか.る
  boom, prosper, copulate"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "盛ん", back: "さかん
  popular;
  prosperous;
  enthusiastic;
  energetic; vigorous"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "密か", back: "ひそか
  secret; private; surreptitious"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "著す", back: "あらわす
  to write; to publish"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "著しい", back: "いちじるしい
  striking; remarkable; considerable (used for good, bad, and neutral observations)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "欲する", back: "ほっする
  to want; to desire"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "欲しい", back: "ほしい
  wanted; wished for; in need of; desired;  
    (Auxiliary adjective) (after the -te form of a verb) I want (you) to"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "探る", back: "さぐる
  to feel around for; to fumble for; to grope for; to search for; to look for;
  to investigate; to probe into; to spy on; to sound out;
  to explore (parts unknown); to enjoy (natural beauty)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "探す", back: "さがす
  to search (for something lost); to seek (a suspect in a crime);
  to search (for something desired, needed); to look for"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "閉じる", back: "とじる
  to close (e.g. book, eyes, meeting, etc.); to shut"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "閉ざす", back: "とざす
  to shut; to close; to lock; to fasten;
  to plunge (in grief)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "閉める", back: "しめる
  to close; to shut"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "閉まる", back: "しまる
  to be shut; to close; to be closed;
  to be locked;
  to tighten; to be tightened;
  to become sober; to become tense"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "閉てる", back: "たてる
  to shut; to close"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "捨てる", back: "すてる
  to throw away; to cast aside; to abandon; to resign; to break up with (someone)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "頂く", back: "いただく
    (Humble (kenjougo) language)  to receive; to get; to accept; to take; to buy;
    (Humble (kenjougo) language)   (Polite language)  to eat; to drink;
  to be crowned with; to wear (on one's head); to have (on top);
  to have (as one's leader); to live under (a ruler); to install (a president)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "裁つ", back: "たつ
  to cut (cloth)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "裁く", back: "さばく
  to judge"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "割る", back: "わる
  to divide; to cut; to break; to halve; to separate; to split; to rip; to crack; to smash; to dilute"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "割り", back: "わり
  rate; ratio; proportion; percentage;
  profit;
  assignment;
  10%; unit of ten percent;
  sumo match; schedule of sumo matches;  
    (Noun suffix) diluted with (of drinks); mixed with"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "割れる", back: "われる
  to break; to be smashed;
  to split; to crack; to fissure; to be torn;
  to be divided; to cleave;
  to come to light; to be identified; to be established; to become clear"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "割く", back: "さく
  to cut up; to cleave; to cut open (esp. the abdomen);
  to spare (time, money, etc.); to use part of something;
    (Archaism)  to have a tattoo in the corner of one's eye"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "補う", back: "おぎなう
  to compensate for; to supplement"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "衆い", back: "おお.い
  masses, great numbers, multitude, populace"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "就く", back: "つく
  to ascend (the throne); to accede;
  to take (seat, position, course, etc.); to assume;
  to start (on a journey); to commence; to depart;
  to study (under teacher); to be an apprentice"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "就ける", back: "つける
  to install (a king, emperor, etc.);
  to appoint (to a post);
  to assign (to study under)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "装う", back: "よそお.う
  attire, dress, pretend, disguise, profess"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "装い", back: "よそおい
  dress; outfit; equipment; makeup; adornment; guise; get-up"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "創る", back: "つくる
  to make; to produce; to manufacture; to build; to construct;
  to prepare  (Food term) ; to brew (alcohol);
  to raise; to grow; to cultivate; to train;
  to till;
  to draw up (a document); to make out; to prepare; to write;
  to create (an artistic work, etc.); to compose;
  to coin (a phrase); to organize; to organise; to establish; to found;
  to have (a child);
  to make up (one's face, etc.);
  to fabricate (an excuse, etc.);
  to form (a line, etc.);
  to set (a record);
  to commit (a sin, etc.)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "創める", back: "はじめる
  to start; to begin; to commence; to initiate; to originate;
  to open (e.g. a store); to start up; to establish (business. etc.);  
    (Auxiliary verb) to start (doing something); to begin to ..."),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "創しける", back: "けず.しける
  genesis, wound, injury, hurt, start, originate"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "善い", back: "よ.い, い.い
  virtuous, good, goodness"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "善く", back: "よく
    (Usually written using kana alone)  nicely; properly; well; skillfully;
  frequently; often"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "善とする", back: "よし.とする
  virtuous, good, goodness"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "勤める", back: "つとめる
  to work (for); to be employed (at); to serve (in);
  to serve (as); to act (as); to fill (the position of); to play the role (of);
  to conduct a religious service"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "勤め", back: "つとめ
  service; duty; business; responsibility; task;
  Buddhist religious services"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "勤まる", back: "つとまる
  to be fit for; to be equal to; to function properly"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "勤しむ", back: "いそしむ
  to endeavor; to endeavour; to work hard (at)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "痛い", back: "いたい
  painful; sore;  
    () exceeding"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "痛む", back: "いたむ
  to hurt; to feel a pain; to be injured"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "痛ましい", back: "いたましい
  pitiful; heartbreaking; tragical"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "痛める", back: "いた.める
  pain, hurt, damage, bruise"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "揮う", back: "ふるう
  to swing; to wield (physically); to exert;
  to exercise; to wield (metaphorically);
  to flourish; to prosper; to thrive"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "貴い", back: "たっと.い, とうと.い
  precious, value, prize, esteem, honor"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "貴ぶ", back: "たっと.ぶ, とうと.ぶ
  precious, value, prize, esteem, honor"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "敬う", back: "うやまう
  to show respect; to honour; to honor"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "尊い", back: "たっと.い, とうと.い
  revered, valuable, precious, noble, exalted"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "尊ぶ", back: "たっと.ぶ, とうと.ぶ
  revered, valuable, precious, noble, exalted"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "傷む", back: "いたむ
  to be damaged; to go bad"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "傷める", back: "いためる
  to damage; to impair; to spoil"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "暖か", back: "あたた.か
  warmth"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "暖かい", back: "あたた.かい
  warmth"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "暖まる", back: "あたたまる
  to warm oneself; to sun oneself; to warm up; to get warm"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "暖める", back: "あたためる
  to warm; to heat"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "蒸す", back: "むす
  to steam; to poultice; to be sultry"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "蒸れる", back: "むれる
  to be stuffy; to moulder; to molder"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "蒸らす", back: "むらす
  to cook by steam"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "認める", back: "みと.める, したた.める
  acknowledge, witness, discern, recognize, appreciate, believe"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "疑う", back: "うたがう
  to doubt; to distrust; to be suspicious of; to suspect"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "遺す", back: "のこす
  to leave (behind, over); to bequeath; to save; to reserve"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "障る", back: "さわる
  to hinder; to interfere with; to affect; to do one harm; to be harmful to"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "暮れる", back: "くれる
  to get dark;
  to end; to come to an end; to close; to run out;
  to be sunk (e.g. in despair); to be lost"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "暮らす", back: "くらす
  to live; to get along;
  to spend (time)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "誤る", back: "あやまる
  to make a mistake; to err;
  to mislead; to misguide"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "権る", back: "はか.る
  authority, power, rights"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "蔵める", back: "おさ.める
  storehouse, hide, own, have, possess"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "蔵れる", back: "かく.れる
  storehouse, hide, own, have, possess"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "熟れる", back: "う.れる
  mellow, ripen, mature, acquire skill"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "激しい", back: "はげしい
  violent; vehement; intense; furious; tempestuous"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "操る", back: "あやつる
  to manipulate; to operate; to handle; to operate (e.g. a machine); to steer (a ship);
  to have a good command of (a language); to be fluent in;
  to operate a puppet; to pull the strings of a puppet;
  to mastermind; to pull the strings; to control from the shadows;
    (Archaism)  to play (a musical instrument)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "奮う", back: "ふるう
  to show (ability); to wield (power);
  to screw up one's courage"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "優しい", back: "やさしい
  tender; kind; gentle; graceful; affectionate; amiable; suave"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "優れる", back: "すぐれる
  to surpass; to outstrip; to excel"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "優る", back: "まさる
  to excel; to surpass; to exceed; to have an edge; to be superior; to outrival;
  to outweigh; to preponderate"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "厳か", back: "おごそか
  austere; majestic; dignified; stately; awful; impressive"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "厳しい", back: "きび.しい
  stern, strictness, severity, rigidity"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "厳めしい", back: "いかめしい
  severe; strict; rigid; unsparing; relentless;
  stern; austere; grave; solemn; majestic;
  intense (cold)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "縮む", back: "ちぢ.む
  shrink, contract, shrivel, wrinkle, reduce"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "縮まる", back: "ちぢまる
  to shorten; to narrow; to close"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "縮める", back: "ちぢめる
  to shorten; to reduce; to boil down; to shrink"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "縮れる", back: "ちぢれる
  to be wavy; to be curled"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "縮らす", back: "ちぢらす
  to curl; to crimp"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "覧る", back: "み.る
  perusal, see"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "難い", back: "かた.い, -がた.い, -にく.い
  difficult, impossible, trouble, accident, defect"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "難しい", back: "むずか.しい, むづか.しい, むつか.しい
  difficult, impossible, trouble, accident, defect"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "臨む", back: "のぞむ
  to look out on;
  to face;
  to deal with;
  to attend (e.g. function); to appear (e.g. in court)"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "簡ぶ", back: "えら.ぶ
  simplicity, brevity"),
  Fuda.find_or_create_by(front: "警める", back: "いましめる
  to admonish; to warn; to remonstrate;
  to prohibit; to forbid;
    (Archaism)  to be cautious;
    (Archaism)  to punish")
  ]
end
